{"Aptitude": {"Problems On Trains": [{"ans": "D", "question": "A train running at the speed of 60 km/hr crosses a pole in 9 seconds. What is the length of the train?", "id": 0, "options": ["120 metres", "180 metres", "324 metres", "150 metres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:", "id": 1, "options": ["45 km/hr", "50 km/hr", "54 km/hr", "55 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:\n", "id": 2, "options": ["200 m", "225 m", "245 m", "250 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is:\n", "id": 3, "options": ["1 : 3", "3 : 2", "3 : 4", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train passes a station platform in 36 seconds and a man standing on the platform in 20 seconds. If the speed of the train is 54 km/hr, what is the length of the platform?\r\n", "id": 4, "options": ["120 m", "240 m", "300 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A train running at the speed of 60 km/hr crosses a pole in 9 seconds. What is the length of the train?", "id": 5, "options": ["120 metres", "180 metres", "324 metres", "150 metres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:", "id": 6, "options": ["45 km/hr", "50 km/hr", "54 km/hr", "55 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:\n", "id": 7, "options": ["200 m", "225 m", "245 m", "250 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is:\n", "id": 8, "options": ["1 : 3", "3 : 2", "3 : 4", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train passes a station platform in 36 seconds and a man standing on the platform in 20 seconds. If the speed of the train is 54 km/hr, what is the length of the platform?\r\n", "id": 9, "options": ["120 m", "240 m", "300 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A train running at the speed of 60 km/hr crosses a pole in 9 seconds. What is the length of the train?", "id": 10, "options": ["120 metres", "180 metres", "324 metres", "150 metres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:", "id": 11, "options": ["45 km/hr", "50 km/hr", "54 km/hr", "55 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:\n", "id": 12, "options": ["200 m", "225 m", "245 m", "250 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is:\n", "id": 13, "options": ["1 : 3", "3 : 2", "3 : 4", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train passes a station platform in 36 seconds and a man standing on the platform in 20 seconds. If the speed of the train is 54 km/hr, what is the length of the platform?\r\n", "id": 14, "options": ["120 m", "240 m", "300 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A train running at the speed of 60 km/hr crosses a pole in 9 seconds. What is the length of the train?", "id": 15, "options": ["120 metres", "180 metres", "324 metres", "150 metres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:", "id": 16, "options": ["45 km/hr", "50 km/hr", "54 km/hr", "55 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:\n", "id": 17, "options": ["200 m", "225 m", "245 m", "250 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is:\n", "id": 18, "options": ["1 : 3", "3 : 2", "3 : 4", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train passes a station platform in 36 seconds and a man standing on the platform in 20 seconds. If the speed of the train is 54 km/hr, what is the length of the platform?\r\n", "id": 19, "options": ["120 m", "240 m", "300 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A train running at the speed of 60 km/hr crosses a pole in 9 seconds. What is the length of the train?", "id": 20, "options": ["120 metres", "180 metres", "324 metres", "150 metres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:", "id": 21, "options": ["45 km/hr", "50 km/hr", "54 km/hr", "55 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:\n", "id": 22, "options": ["200 m", "225 m", "245 m", "250 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is:\n", "id": 23, "options": ["1 : 3", "3 : 2", "3 : 4", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train passes a station platform in 36 seconds and a man standing on the platform in 20 seconds. If the speed of the train is 54 km/hr, what is the length of the platform?\r\n", "id": 24, "options": ["120 m", "240 m", "300 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A train running at the speed of 60 km/hr crosses a pole in 9 seconds. What is the length of the train?", "id": 25, "options": ["120 metres", "180 metres", "324 metres", "150 metres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:", "id": 26, "options": ["45 km/hr", "50 km/hr", "54 km/hr", "55 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:\n", "id": 27, "options": ["200 m", "225 m", "245 m", "250 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is:\n", "id": 28, "options": ["1 : 3", "3 : 2", "3 : 4", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train passes a station platform in 36 seconds and a man standing on the platform in 20 seconds. If the speed of the train is 54 km/hr, what is the length of the platform?\r\n", "id": 29, "options": ["120 m", "240 m", "300 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A train running at the speed of 60 km/hr crosses a pole in 9 seconds. What is the length of the train?", "id": 30, "options": ["120 metres", "180 metres", "324 metres", "150 metres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:", "id": 31, "options": ["45 km/hr", "50 km/hr", "54 km/hr", "55 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:\n", "id": 32, "options": ["200 m", "225 m", "245 m", "250 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is:\n", "id": 33, "options": ["1 : 3", "3 : 2", "3 : 4", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A train passes a station platform in 36 seconds and a man standing on the platform in 20 seconds. If the speed of the train is 54 km/hr, what is the length of the platform?\r\n", "id": 34, "options": ["120 m", "240 m", "300 m", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Height And Distance": [{"ans": "C", "question": "Two ships are sailing in the sea on the two sides of a lighthouse. The angle of elevation of the top of the lighthouse is observed from the ships are 30\u00b0 and 45\u00b0 respectively. If the lighthouse is 100 m high, the distance between the two ships is:", "id": 35, "options": ["173 m", "200 m", "273 m", "300 m"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA man standing at a point P is watching the top of a tower, which makes an angle of elevation of 30\u00ba with the man's eye. The man walks some distance towards the tower to watch its top and the angle of the elevation becomes 60\u00ba. What is the distance between the base of the tower and the point P?\n", "id": 36, "options": ["43 units", "8 units", "12 units", "Data inadequate", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe angle of elevation of a ladder leaning against a wall is 60\u00ba and the foot of the ladder is 4.6 m away from the wall. The length of the ladder is:\n", "id": 37, "options": ["2.3 m", "4.6 m", "7.8 m", "9.2 m"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nAn observer 1.6 m tall is 203 away from a tower. The angle of elevation from his eye to the top of the tower is 30\u00ba. The heights of the tower is:\n", "id": 38, "options": ["21.6 m", "23.2 m", "24.72 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nFrom a point P on a level ground, the angle of elevation of the top tower is 30\u00ba. If the tower is 100 m high, the distance of point P from the foot of the tower is:\n", "id": 39, "options": ["149 m", "156 m", "173 m", "200 m"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Two ships are sailing in the sea on the two sides of a lighthouse. The angle of elevation of the top of the lighthouse is observed from the ships are 30\u00b0 and 45\u00b0 respectively. If the lighthouse is 100 m high, the distance between the two ships is:", "id": 40, "options": ["173 m", "200 m", "273 m", "300 m"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA man standing at a point P is watching the top of a tower, which makes an angle of elevation of 30\u00ba with the man's eye. The man walks some distance towards the tower to watch its top and the angle of the elevation becomes 60\u00ba. What is the distance between the base of the tower and the point P?\n", "id": 41, "options": ["43 units", "8 units", "12 units", "Data inadequate", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe angle of elevation of a ladder leaning against a wall is 60\u00ba and the foot of the ladder is 4.6 m away from the wall. The length of the ladder is:\n", "id": 42, "options": ["2.3 m", "4.6 m", "7.8 m", "9.2 m"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nAn observer 1.6 m tall is 203 away from a tower. The angle of elevation from his eye to the top of the tower is 30\u00ba. The heights of the tower is:\n", "id": 43, "options": ["21.6 m", "23.2 m", "24.72 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nFrom a point P on a level ground, the angle of elevation of the top tower is 30\u00ba. If the tower is 100 m high, the distance of point P from the foot of the tower is:\n", "id": 44, "options": ["149 m", "156 m", "173 m", "200 m"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Simple Interest": [{"ans": "C", "question": "\nA sum of money at simple interest amounts to Rs. 815 in 3 years and to Rs. 854 in 4 years. The sum is:\n", "id": 45, "options": ["Rs. 650", "Rs. 690", "Rs. 698", "Rs. 700"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Mr. Thomas invested an amount of Rs. 13,900 divided in two different schemes A and B at the simple interest rate of 14% p.a. and 11% p.a. respectively. If the total amount of simple interest earned in 2 years be Rs. 3508, what was the amount invested in Scheme B?\r\n", "id": 46, "options": ["Rs. 6400", "Rs. 6500", "Rs. 7200", "Rs. 7500", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA sum fetched a total simple interest of Rs. 4016.25 at the rate of 9 p.c.p.a. in 5 years. What is the sum?\n", "id": 47, "options": ["Rs. 4462.50", "Rs. 8032.50", "Rs. 8900", "Rs. 8925", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nHow much time will it take for an amount of Rs. 450 to yield Rs. 81 as interest at 4.5% per annum of simple interest?\n", "id": 48, "options": ["3.5 years", "4 years", "4.5 years", "5 years"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nReena took a loan of Rs. 1200 with simple interest for as many years as the rate of interest. If she paid Rs. 432 as interest at the end of the loan period, what was the rate of interest?\n", "id": 49, "options": ["3.6", "6", "18", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA sum of money at simple interest amounts to Rs. 815 in 3 years and to Rs. 854 in 4 years. The sum is:\n", "id": 50, "options": ["Rs. 650", "Rs. 690", "Rs. 698", "Rs. 700"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Mr. Thomas invested an amount of Rs. 13,900 divided in two different schemes A and B at the simple interest rate of 14% p.a. and 11% p.a. respectively. If the total amount of simple interest earned in 2 years be Rs. 3508, what was the amount invested in Scheme B?\r\n", "id": 51, "options": ["Rs. 6400", "Rs. 6500", "Rs. 7200", "Rs. 7500", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA sum fetched a total simple interest of Rs. 4016.25 at the rate of 9 p.c.p.a. in 5 years. What is the sum?\n", "id": 52, "options": ["Rs. 4462.50", "Rs. 8032.50", "Rs. 8900", "Rs. 8925", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nHow much time will it take for an amount of Rs. 450 to yield Rs. 81 as interest at 4.5% per annum of simple interest?\n", "id": 53, "options": ["3.5 years", "4 years", "4.5 years", "5 years"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nReena took a loan of Rs. 1200 with simple interest for as many years as the rate of interest. If she paid Rs. 432 as interest at the end of the loan period, what was the rate of interest?\n", "id": 54, "options": ["3.6", "6", "18", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA sum of money at simple interest amounts to Rs. 815 in 3 years and to Rs. 854 in 4 years. The sum is:\n", "id": 55, "options": ["Rs. 650", "Rs. 690", "Rs. 698", "Rs. 700"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Mr. Thomas invested an amount of Rs. 13,900 divided in two different schemes A and B at the simple interest rate of 14% p.a. and 11% p.a. respectively. If the total amount of simple interest earned in 2 years be Rs. 3508, what was the amount invested in Scheme B?\r\n", "id": 56, "options": ["Rs. 6400", "Rs. 6500", "Rs. 7200", "Rs. 7500", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA sum fetched a total simple interest of Rs. 4016.25 at the rate of 9 p.c.p.a. in 5 years. What is the sum?\n", "id": 57, "options": ["Rs. 4462.50", "Rs. 8032.50", "Rs. 8900", "Rs. 8925", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nHow much time will it take for an amount of Rs. 450 to yield Rs. 81 as interest at 4.5% per annum of simple interest?\n", "id": 58, "options": ["3.5 years", "4 years", "4.5 years", "5 years"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nReena took a loan of Rs. 1200 with simple interest for as many years as the rate of interest. If she paid Rs. 432 as interest at the end of the loan period, what was the rate of interest?\n", "id": 59, "options": ["3.6", "6", "18", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Profit And Loss": [{"ans": "B", "question": "Alfred buys an old scooter for Rs. 4700 and spends Rs. 800 on its repairs. If he sells the scooter for Rs. 5800, his gain percent is:\n", "id": 60, "options": ["\n\n\n4\n4\n%\n\n\n7\n\n\n", "\n\n\n5\n5\n%\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "10%", "12%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe cost price of 20 articles is the same as the selling price of x articles. If the profit is 25%, then the value of x is:\n", "id": 61, "options": ["15", "16", "18", "25"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "If selling price is doubled, the profit triples. Find the profit percent.", "id": 62, "options": ["\n\n66\n2\n\n\n3\n\n", "100", "\n\n105\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "120"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "In a certain store, the profit is 320% of the cost. If the cost increases by 25% but the selling price remains constant, approximately what percentage of the selling price is the profit?", "id": 63, "options": ["30%", "70%", "100%", "250%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA vendor bought toffees at 6 for a rupee. How many for a rupee must he sell to gain 20%?\n", "id": 64, "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Alfred buys an old scooter for Rs. 4700 and spends Rs. 800 on its repairs. If he sells the scooter for Rs. 5800, his gain percent is:\n", "id": 65, "options": ["\n\n\n4\n4\n%\n\n\n7\n\n\n", "\n\n\n5\n5\n%\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "10%", "12%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe cost price of 20 articles is the same as the selling price of x articles. If the profit is 25%, then the value of x is:\n", "id": 66, "options": ["15", "16", "18", "25"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "If selling price is doubled, the profit triples. Find the profit percent.", "id": 67, "options": ["\n\n66\n2\n\n\n3\n\n", "100", "\n\n105\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "120"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "In a certain store, the profit is 320% of the cost. If the cost increases by 25% but the selling price remains constant, approximately what percentage of the selling price is the profit?", "id": 68, "options": ["30%", "70%", "100%", "250%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA vendor bought toffees at 6 for a rupee. How many for a rupee must he sell to gain 20%?\n", "id": 69, "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Alfred buys an old scooter for Rs. 4700 and spends Rs. 800 on its repairs. If he sells the scooter for Rs. 5800, his gain percent is:\n", "id": 70, "options": ["\n\n\n4\n4\n%\n\n\n7\n\n\n", "\n\n\n5\n5\n%\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "10%", "12%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe cost price of 20 articles is the same as the selling price of x articles. If the profit is 25%, then the value of x is:\n", "id": 71, "options": ["15", "16", "18", "25"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "If selling price is doubled, the profit triples. Find the profit percent.", "id": 72, "options": ["\n\n66\n2\n\n\n3\n\n", "100", "\n\n105\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "120"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "In a certain store, the profit is 320% of the cost. If the cost increases by 25% but the selling price remains constant, approximately what percentage of the selling price is the profit?", "id": 73, "options": ["30%", "70%", "100%", "250%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA vendor bought toffees at 6 for a rupee. How many for a rupee must he sell to gain 20%?\n", "id": 74, "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Percentage": [{"ans": "B", "question": "A batsman scored 110 runs which included 3 boundaries and 8 sixes. What percent of his total score did he make by running between the wickets?", "id": 75, "options": ["45%", "\n\n45\n5\n%\n\n\n11\n\n", "\n\n54\n6\n%\n\n\n11\n\n", "55%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nTwo students appeared at an examination. One of them secured 9 marks more than the other and his marks was 56% of the sum of their marks. The marks obtained by them are:\n", "id": 76, "options": ["39, 30", "41, 32", "42, 33", "43, 34"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA fruit seller had some apples. He sells 40% apples and still has 420 apples. Originally, he had:\n", "id": 77, "options": ["588 apples", "600 apples", "672 apples", "700 apples"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What percentage of numbers from 1 to 70 have 1 or 9 in the unit's digit?", "id": 78, "options": ["1", "14", "20", "21"]}, {"ans": "E", "question": "\nIf A = x% of y and B = y% of x, then which of the following is true?\n", "id": 79, "options": ["A is smaller than B.", "A is greater than B", "Relationship between A and B cannot be determined.", "If x is smaller than y, then A is greater than B.", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A batsman scored 110 runs which included 3 boundaries and 8 sixes. What percent of his total score did he make by running between the wickets?", "id": 80, "options": ["45%", "\n\n45\n5\n%\n\n\n11\n\n", "\n\n54\n6\n%\n\n\n11\n\n", "55%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nTwo students appeared at an examination. One of them secured 9 marks more than the other and his marks was 56% of the sum of their marks. The marks obtained by them are:\n", "id": 81, "options": ["39, 30", "41, 32", "42, 33", "43, 34"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA fruit seller had some apples. He sells 40% apples and still has 420 apples. Originally, he had:\n", "id": 82, "options": ["588 apples", "600 apples", "672 apples", "700 apples"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What percentage of numbers from 1 to 70 have 1 or 9 in the unit's digit?", "id": 83, "options": ["1", "14", "20", "21"]}, {"ans": "E", "question": "\nIf A = x% of y and B = y% of x, then which of the following is true?\n", "id": 84, "options": ["A is smaller than B.", "A is greater than B", "Relationship between A and B cannot be determined.", "If x is smaller than y, then A is greater than B.", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A batsman scored 110 runs which included 3 boundaries and 8 sixes. What percent of his total score did he make by running between the wickets?", "id": 85, "options": ["45%", "\n\n45\n5\n%\n\n\n11\n\n", "\n\n54\n6\n%\n\n\n11\n\n", "55%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nTwo students appeared at an examination. One of them secured 9 marks more than the other and his marks was 56% of the sum of their marks. The marks obtained by them are:\n", "id": 86, "options": ["39, 30", "41, 32", "42, 33", "43, 34"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA fruit seller had some apples. He sells 40% apples and still has 420 apples. Originally, he had:\n", "id": 87, "options": ["588 apples", "600 apples", "672 apples", "700 apples"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What percentage of numbers from 1 to 70 have 1 or 9 in the unit's digit?", "id": 88, "options": ["1", "14", "20", "21"]}, {"ans": "E", "question": "\nIf A = x% of y and B = y% of x, then which of the following is true?\n", "id": 89, "options": ["A is smaller than B.", "A is greater than B", "Relationship between A and B cannot be determined.", "If x is smaller than y, then A is greater than B.", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Calendar": [{"ans": "C", "question": "\nIt was Sunday on Jan 1, 2006. What was the day of the week Jan 1, 2010?\n", "id": 90, "options": ["Sunday", "Saturday", "Friday", "Wednesday"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhat was the day of the week on 28th May, 2006?\n", "id": 91, "options": ["Thursday", "Friday", "Saturday", "Sunday"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What was the day of the week on 17th June, 1998?\r\n", "id": 92, "options": ["Monday", "Tuesday", "Wednesday", "Thursday"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nWhat will be the day of the week 15th August, 2010?\n", "id": 93, "options": ["Sunday", "Monday", "Tuesday", "Friday"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nToday is Monday. After 61 days, it will be:\n", "id": 94, "options": ["Wednesday", "Saturday", "Tuesday", "Thursday"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIt was Sunday on Jan 1, 2006. What was the day of the week Jan 1, 2010?\n", "id": 95, "options": ["Sunday", "Saturday", "Friday", "Wednesday"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhat was the day of the week on 28th May, 2006?\n", "id": 96, "options": ["Thursday", "Friday", "Saturday", "Sunday"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What was the day of the week on 17th June, 1998?\r\n", "id": 97, "options": ["Monday", "Tuesday", "Wednesday", "Thursday"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nWhat will be the day of the week 15th August, 2010?\n", "id": 98, "options": ["Sunday", "Monday", "Tuesday", "Friday"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nToday is Monday. After 61 days, it will be:\n", "id": 99, "options": ["Wednesday", "Saturday", "Tuesday", "Thursday"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIt was Sunday on Jan 1, 2006. What was the day of the week Jan 1, 2010?\n", "id": 100, "options": ["Sunday", "Saturday", "Friday", "Wednesday"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhat was the day of the week on 28th May, 2006?\n", "id": 101, "options": ["Thursday", "Friday", "Saturday", "Sunday"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What was the day of the week on 17th June, 1998?\r\n", "id": 102, "options": ["Monday", "Tuesday", "Wednesday", "Thursday"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nWhat will be the day of the week 15th August, 2010?\n", "id": 103, "options": ["Sunday", "Monday", "Tuesday", "Friday"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nToday is Monday. After 61 days, it will be:\n", "id": 104, "options": ["Wednesday", "Saturday", "Tuesday", "Thursday"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Average": [{"ans": "A", "question": "\nIn the first 10 overs of a cricket game, the run rate was only 3.2. What should be the run rate in the remaining 40 overs to reach the target of 282 runs?\n", "id": 105, "options": ["6.25", "6.5", "6.75", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A family consists of two grandparents, two parents and three grandchildren. The average age of the grandparents is 67 years, that of the parents is 35 years and that of the grandchildren is 6 years. What is the average age of the family?", "id": 106, "options": ["\n\n28\u00a0\n4\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n31\u00a0\n5\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n32\u00a0\n1\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA grocer has a sale of Rs. 6435, Rs. 6927, Rs. 6855, Rs. 7230 and Rs. 6562 for 5 consecutive months. How much sale must he have in the sixth month so that he gets an average sale of Rs. 6500?\n", "id": 107, "options": ["Rs. 4991", "Rs. 5991", "Rs. 6001", "Rs. 6991"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe average of 20 numbers is zero. Of them, at the most, how many may be greater than zero?\n", "id": 108, "options": ["0", "1", "10", "19"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe average weight of 8 person's increases by 2.5 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 65 kg. What might be the weight of the new person?\n", "id": 109, "options": ["76 kg", "76.5 kg", "85 kg", "Data inadequate", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIn the first 10 overs of a cricket game, the run rate was only 3.2. What should be the run rate in the remaining 40 overs to reach the target of 282 runs?\n", "id": 110, "options": ["6.25", "6.5", "6.75", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A family consists of two grandparents, two parents and three grandchildren. The average age of the grandparents is 67 years, that of the parents is 35 years and that of the grandchildren is 6 years. What is the average age of the family?", "id": 111, "options": ["\n\n28\u00a0\n4\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n31\u00a0\n5\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n32\u00a0\n1\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA grocer has a sale of Rs. 6435, Rs. 6927, Rs. 6855, Rs. 7230 and Rs. 6562 for 5 consecutive months. How much sale must he have in the sixth month so that he gets an average sale of Rs. 6500?\n", "id": 112, "options": ["Rs. 4991", "Rs. 5991", "Rs. 6001", "Rs. 6991"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe average of 20 numbers is zero. Of them, at the most, how many may be greater than zero?\n", "id": 113, "options": ["0", "1", "10", "19"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe average weight of 8 person's increases by 2.5 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 65 kg. What might be the weight of the new person?\n", "id": 114, "options": ["76 kg", "76.5 kg", "85 kg", "Data inadequate", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIn the first 10 overs of a cricket game, the run rate was only 3.2. What should be the run rate in the remaining 40 overs to reach the target of 282 runs?\n", "id": 115, "options": ["6.25", "6.5", "6.75", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A family consists of two grandparents, two parents and three grandchildren. The average age of the grandparents is 67 years, that of the parents is 35 years and that of the grandchildren is 6 years. What is the average age of the family?", "id": 116, "options": ["\n\n28\u00a0\n4\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n31\u00a0\n5\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n32\u00a0\n1\nyears\n\n\n7\n\n", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA grocer has a sale of Rs. 6435, Rs. 6927, Rs. 6855, Rs. 7230 and Rs. 6562 for 5 consecutive months. How much sale must he have in the sixth month so that he gets an average sale of Rs. 6500?\n", "id": 117, "options": ["Rs. 4991", "Rs. 5991", "Rs. 6001", "Rs. 6991"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe average of 20 numbers is zero. Of them, at the most, how many may be greater than zero?\n", "id": 118, "options": ["0", "1", "10", "19"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe average weight of 8 person's increases by 2.5 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 65 kg. What might be the weight of the new person?\n", "id": 119, "options": ["76 kg", "76.5 kg", "85 kg", "Data inadequate", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Volume And Surface Area": [{"ans": "A", "question": "A right triangle with sides 3 cm, 4 cm and 5 cm is rotated the side of 3 cm to form a cone. The volume of the cone so formed is:", "id": 120, "options": ["12 cm3", "15 cm3", "16 cm3", "20 cm3"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "In a shower, 5 cm of rain falls. The volume of water that falls on 1.5 hectares of ground is:", "id": 121, "options": ["75 cu. m", "750 cu. m", "7500 cu. m", "75000 cu. m"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A hall is 15 m long and 12 m broad. If the sum of the areas of the floor and the ceiling is equal to the sum of the areas of four walls, the volume of the hall is:\r\n", "id": 122, "options": ["720", "900", "1200", "1800"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n66 cubic centimetres of silver is drawn into a wire 1 mm in diameter. The length of the wire in metres will be:\n", "id": 123, "options": ["84", "90", "168", "336"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA hollow iron pipe is 21 cm long and its external diameter is 8 cm. If the thickness of the pipe is 1 cm and iron weighs 8 g/cm3, then the weight of the pipe is:\n", "id": 124, "options": ["3.6 kg", "3.696 kg", "36 kg", "36.9 kg"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "A right triangle with sides 3 cm, 4 cm and 5 cm is rotated the side of 3 cm to form a cone. The volume of the cone so formed is:", "id": 125, "options": ["12 cm3", "15 cm3", "16 cm3", "20 cm3"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "In a shower, 5 cm of rain falls. The volume of water that falls on 1.5 hectares of ground is:", "id": 126, "options": ["75 cu. m", "750 cu. m", "7500 cu. m", "75000 cu. m"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A hall is 15 m long and 12 m broad. If the sum of the areas of the floor and the ceiling is equal to the sum of the areas of four walls, the volume of the hall is:\r\n", "id": 127, "options": ["720", "900", "1200", "1800"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n66 cubic centimetres of silver is drawn into a wire 1 mm in diameter. The length of the wire in metres will be:\n", "id": 128, "options": ["84", "90", "168", "336"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA hollow iron pipe is 21 cm long and its external diameter is 8 cm. If the thickness of the pipe is 1 cm and iron weighs 8 g/cm3, then the weight of the pipe is:\n", "id": 129, "options": ["3.6 kg", "3.696 kg", "36 kg", "36.9 kg"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "A right triangle with sides 3 cm, 4 cm and 5 cm is rotated the side of 3 cm to form a cone. The volume of the cone so formed is:", "id": 130, "options": ["12 cm3", "15 cm3", "16 cm3", "20 cm3"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "In a shower, 5 cm of rain falls. The volume of water that falls on 1.5 hectares of ground is:", "id": 131, "options": ["75 cu. m", "750 cu. m", "7500 cu. m", "75000 cu. m"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A hall is 15 m long and 12 m broad. If the sum of the areas of the floor and the ceiling is equal to the sum of the areas of four walls, the volume of the hall is:\r\n", "id": 132, "options": ["720", "900", "1200", "1800"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n66 cubic centimetres of silver is drawn into a wire 1 mm in diameter. The length of the wire in metres will be:\n", "id": 133, "options": ["84", "90", "168", "336"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA hollow iron pipe is 21 cm long and its external diameter is 8 cm. If the thickness of the pipe is 1 cm and iron weighs 8 g/cm3, then the weight of the pipe is:\n", "id": 134, "options": ["3.6 kg", "3.696 kg", "36 kg", "36.9 kg"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Numbers": [{"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 135, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 136, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 137, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 138, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 139, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 140, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 141, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 142, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 143, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 144, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 145, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 146, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 147, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 148, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 149, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 150, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 151, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 152, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 153, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 154, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 155, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 156, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 157, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 158, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 159, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 160, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 161, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 162, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 163, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 164, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 165, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 166, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 167, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 168, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 169, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 170, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 171, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 172, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 173, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 174, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 175, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 176, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 177, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 178, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 179, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 180, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 181, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 182, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 183, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 184, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 185, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 186, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 187, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 188, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 189, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 190, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 191, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 192, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 193, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 194, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 195, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 196, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 197, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 198, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 199, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 200, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 201, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 202, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 203, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 204, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 205, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 206, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 207, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 208, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 209, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 210, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 211, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 212, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 213, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 214, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 215, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 216, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 217, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 218, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 219, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 220, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 221, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 222, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 223, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 224, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 225, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 226, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 227, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 228, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 229, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 230, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 231, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 232, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 233, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 234, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 235, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 236, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 237, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 238, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 239, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 240, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 241, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 242, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 243, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 244, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 245, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 246, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 247, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 248, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 249, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 250, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 251, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 252, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 253, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 254, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 255, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 256, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 257, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 258, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 259, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 260, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 261, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 262, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 263, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 264, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Which one of the following is not a prime number?", "id": 265, "options": ["31", "61", "71", "91"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(112 x 54) = ?\n", "id": 266, "options": ["67000", "70000", "76500", "77200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "It is being given that (232 + 1) is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?", "id": 267, "options": ["(216 + 1)", "(216 - 1)", "(7 x 223)", "(296 + 1)"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What least number must be added to 1056, so that the sum is completely divisible by 23 ?", "id": 268, "options": ["2", "3", "18", "21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n1397 x 1397 = ?\n", "id": 269, "options": ["1951609", "1981709", "18362619", "2031719", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How many of the following numbers are divisible by 132 ?\n264, 396, 462, 792, 968, 2178, 5184, 6336", "id": 270, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n(935421 x 625) = ?\n", "id": 271, "options": ["575648125", "584638125", "584649125", "585628125"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "The largest 4 digit number exactly divisible by 88 is:", "id": 272, "options": ["9944", "9768", "9988", "8888", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nWhich of the following is a prime number ?\n", "id": 273, "options": ["33", "81", "93", "97"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the unit digit in {(6374)1793 x (625)317 x (341491)}?", "id": 274, "options": ["0\u00a0", "2", "3", "5"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Problems On Hcf And Lcm": [{"ans": "A", "question": "\nFind the greatest number that will divide 43, 91 and 183 so as to leave the same remainder in each case.\n", "id": 275, "options": ["4", "7", "9", "13"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe H.C.F. of two numbers is 23 and the other two factors of their L.C.M. are 13 and 14. The larger of the two numbers is:\n", "id": 276, "options": ["276", "299", "322", "345"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nSix bells commence tolling together and toll at intervals of 2, 4, 6, 8 10 and 12 seconds respectively. In 30 minutes, how many times do they toll together ?\n", "id": 277, "options": ["4", "10", "15", "16"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Let N be the greatest number that will divide 1305, 4665 and 6905, leaving the same remainder in each case. Then sum of the digits in N is:\r\n", "id": 278, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe greatest number of four digits which is divisible by 15, 25, 40 and 75 is:\n", "id": 279, "options": ["9000", "9400", "9600", "9800"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nFind the greatest number that will divide 43, 91 and 183 so as to leave the same remainder in each case.\n", "id": 280, "options": ["4", "7", "9", "13"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe H.C.F. of two numbers is 23 and the other two factors of their L.C.M. are 13 and 14. The larger of the two numbers is:\n", "id": 281, "options": ["276", "299", "322", "345"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nSix bells commence tolling together and toll at intervals of 2, 4, 6, 8 10 and 12 seconds respectively. In 30 minutes, how many times do they toll together ?\n", "id": 282, "options": ["4", "10", "15", "16"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Let N be the greatest number that will divide 1305, 4665 and 6905, leaving the same remainder in each case. Then sum of the digits in N is:\r\n", "id": 283, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe greatest number of four digits which is divisible by 15, 25, 40 and 75 is:\n", "id": 284, "options": ["9000", "9400", "9600", "9800"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nFind the greatest number that will divide 43, 91 and 183 so as to leave the same remainder in each case.\n", "id": 285, "options": ["4", "7", "9", "13"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe H.C.F. of two numbers is 23 and the other two factors of their L.C.M. are 13 and 14. The larger of the two numbers is:\n", "id": 286, "options": ["276", "299", "322", "345"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nSix bells commence tolling together and toll at intervals of 2, 4, 6, 8 10 and 12 seconds respectively. In 30 minutes, how many times do they toll together ?\n", "id": 287, "options": ["4", "10", "15", "16"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Let N be the greatest number that will divide 1305, 4665 and 6905, leaving the same remainder in each case. Then sum of the digits in N is:\r\n", "id": 288, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe greatest number of four digits which is divisible by 15, 25, 40 and 75 is:\n", "id": 289, "options": ["9000", "9400", "9600", "9800"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nFind the greatest number that will divide 43, 91 and 183 so as to leave the same remainder in each case.\n", "id": 290, "options": ["4", "7", "9", "13"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe H.C.F. of two numbers is 23 and the other two factors of their L.C.M. are 13 and 14. The larger of the two numbers is:\n", "id": 291, "options": ["276", "299", "322", "345"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nSix bells commence tolling together and toll at intervals of 2, 4, 6, 8 10 and 12 seconds respectively. In 30 minutes, how many times do they toll together ?\n", "id": 292, "options": ["4", "10", "15", "16"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Let N be the greatest number that will divide 1305, 4665 and 6905, leaving the same remainder in each case. Then sum of the digits in N is:\r\n", "id": 293, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe greatest number of four digits which is divisible by 15, 25, 40 and 75 is:\n", "id": 294, "options": ["9000", "9400", "9600", "9800"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nFind the greatest number that will divide 43, 91 and 183 so as to leave the same remainder in each case.\n", "id": 295, "options": ["4", "7", "9", "13"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe H.C.F. of two numbers is 23 and the other two factors of their L.C.M. are 13 and 14. The larger of the two numbers is:\n", "id": 296, "options": ["276", "299", "322", "345"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nSix bells commence tolling together and toll at intervals of 2, 4, 6, 8 10 and 12 seconds respectively. In 30 minutes, how many times do they toll together ?\n", "id": 297, "options": ["4", "10", "15", "16"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Let N be the greatest number that will divide 1305, 4665 and 6905, leaving the same remainder in each case. Then sum of the digits in N is:\r\n", "id": 298, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe greatest number of four digits which is divisible by 15, 25, 40 and 75 is:\n", "id": 299, "options": ["9000", "9400", "9600", "9800"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nFind the greatest number that will divide 43, 91 and 183 so as to leave the same remainder in each case.\n", "id": 300, "options": ["4", "7", "9", "13"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe H.C.F. of two numbers is 23 and the other two factors of their L.C.M. are 13 and 14. The larger of the two numbers is:\n", "id": 301, "options": ["276", "299", "322", "345"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nSix bells commence tolling together and toll at intervals of 2, 4, 6, 8 10 and 12 seconds respectively. In 30 minutes, how many times do they toll together ?\n", "id": 302, "options": ["4", "10", "15", "16"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Let N be the greatest number that will divide 1305, 4665 and 6905, leaving the same remainder in each case. Then sum of the digits in N is:\r\n", "id": 303, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe greatest number of four digits which is divisible by 15, 25, 40 and 75 is:\n", "id": 304, "options": ["9000", "9400", "9600", "9800"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Simplification": [{"ans": "D", "question": "\nA man  has  Rs. 480 in the denominations of one-rupee notes, five-rupee notes and ten-rupee notes. The number of notes of each denomination is equal. What is the total number of notes that he has ?\n", "id": 305, "options": ["45", "60", "75", "90"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThere are two examinations rooms A and B. If 10 students are sent from A to B, then the number of students in each room is the same. If 20 candidates are sent from B to A, then the number of students in A is double the number of students in B. The number of students in room A is:\n", "id": 306, "options": ["20", "80", "100", "200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe price of 10 chairs is equal to that of 4 tables. The price of 15 chairs and 2 tables together is Rs. 4000. The total price of 12 chairs and 3 tables is:\n", "id": 307, "options": ["Rs. 3500", "Rs. 3750", "Rs. 3840", "Rs. 3900"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf a - b = 3 and a2 + b2 = 29, find the value of ab.\n", "id": 308, "options": ["10", "12", "15", "18"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "The price of 2 sarees and 4 shirts is Rs. 1600. With the same money one can buy 1 saree and 6 shirts. If one wants to buy 12 shirts, how much shall he have to pay ?", "id": 309, "options": ["Rs. 1200", "Rs. 2400", "Rs. 4800", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA man  has  Rs. 480 in the denominations of one-rupee notes, five-rupee notes and ten-rupee notes. The number of notes of each denomination is equal. What is the total number of notes that he has ?\n", "id": 310, "options": ["45", "60", "75", "90"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThere are two examinations rooms A and B. If 10 students are sent from A to B, then the number of students in each room is the same. If 20 candidates are sent from B to A, then the number of students in A is double the number of students in B. The number of students in room A is:\n", "id": 311, "options": ["20", "80", "100", "200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe price of 10 chairs is equal to that of 4 tables. The price of 15 chairs and 2 tables together is Rs. 4000. The total price of 12 chairs and 3 tables is:\n", "id": 312, "options": ["Rs. 3500", "Rs. 3750", "Rs. 3840", "Rs. 3900"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf a - b = 3 and a2 + b2 = 29, find the value of ab.\n", "id": 313, "options": ["10", "12", "15", "18"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "The price of 2 sarees and 4 shirts is Rs. 1600. With the same money one can buy 1 saree and 6 shirts. If one wants to buy 12 shirts, how much shall he have to pay ?", "id": 314, "options": ["Rs. 1200", "Rs. 2400", "Rs. 4800", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA man  has  Rs. 480 in the denominations of one-rupee notes, five-rupee notes and ten-rupee notes. The number of notes of each denomination is equal. What is the total number of notes that he has ?\n", "id": 315, "options": ["45", "60", "75", "90"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThere are two examinations rooms A and B. If 10 students are sent from A to B, then the number of students in each room is the same. If 20 candidates are sent from B to A, then the number of students in A is double the number of students in B. The number of students in room A is:\n", "id": 316, "options": ["20", "80", "100", "200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe price of 10 chairs is equal to that of 4 tables. The price of 15 chairs and 2 tables together is Rs. 4000. The total price of 12 chairs and 3 tables is:\n", "id": 317, "options": ["Rs. 3500", "Rs. 3750", "Rs. 3840", "Rs. 3900"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf a - b = 3 and a2 + b2 = 29, find the value of ab.\n", "id": 318, "options": ["10", "12", "15", "18"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "The price of 2 sarees and 4 shirts is Rs. 1600. With the same money one can buy 1 saree and 6 shirts. If one wants to buy 12 shirts, how much shall he have to pay ?", "id": 319, "options": ["Rs. 1200", "Rs. 2400", "Rs. 4800", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Surds And Indices": [{"ans": "D", "question": "(17)3.5 x (17)? = 178\n", "id": 320, "options": ["2.29", "2.75", "4.25", "4.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n\nIf\n\na\n\nx - 1\n=\n\nb\n\nx - 3\n, then the value of x is:\n\n\nb\na\n\n", "id": 321, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n", "1", "2", "\n\n7\n\n\n2\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nGiven that 100.48 = x, 100.70 = y and xz = y2, then the value of z is close to:\n", "id": 322, "options": ["1.45", "1.88", "2.9", "3.7"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf 5a = 3125, then the value of 5(a - 3) is:\n", "id": 323, "options": ["25", "125", "625", "1625"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf 3(x - y) = 27 and 3(x + y) = 243, then x is equal to:\n", "id": 324, "options": ["0", "2", "4", "6"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "(17)3.5 x (17)? = 178\n", "id": 325, "options": ["2.29", "2.75", "4.25", "4.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n\nIf\n\na\n\nx - 1\n=\n\nb\n\nx - 3\n, then the value of x is:\n\n\nb\na\n\n", "id": 326, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n", "1", "2", "\n\n7\n\n\n2\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nGiven that 100.48 = x, 100.70 = y and xz = y2, then the value of z is close to:\n", "id": 327, "options": ["1.45", "1.88", "2.9", "3.7"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf 5a = 3125, then the value of 5(a - 3) is:\n", "id": 328, "options": ["25", "125", "625", "1625"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf 3(x - y) = 27 and 3(x + y) = 243, then x is equal to:\n", "id": 329, "options": ["0", "2", "4", "6"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "(17)3.5 x (17)? = 178\n", "id": 330, "options": ["2.29", "2.75", "4.25", "4.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n\nIf\n\na\n\nx - 1\n=\n\nb\n\nx - 3\n, then the value of x is:\n\n\nb\na\n\n", "id": 331, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n", "1", "2", "\n\n7\n\n\n2\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nGiven that 100.48 = x, 100.70 = y and xz = y2, then the value of z is close to:\n", "id": 332, "options": ["1.45", "1.88", "2.9", "3.7"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf 5a = 3125, then the value of 5(a - 3) is:\n", "id": 333, "options": ["25", "125", "625", "1625"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf 3(x - y) = 27 and 3(x + y) = 243, then x is equal to:\n", "id": 334, "options": ["0", "2", "4", "6"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Chain Rule": [{"ans": "D", "question": "\n3 pumps, working 8 hours a day, can empty a tank in 2 days. How many hours a day must 4 pumps work to empty the tank in 1 day?\n", "id": 335, "options": ["9", "10", "11", "12"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "If the cost of x metres of wire is d rupees, then what is the cost of y metres of wire at the same rate?", "id": 336, "options": ["\n\nRs.\n\nxy\n\n\n\nd\n\n", "Rs. (xd)", "Rs. (yd)", "\n\nRs.\n\nyd\n\n\n\nx\n\n"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nRunning at the same constant rate, 6 identical machines can produce a total of 270 bottles per minute. At this rate, how many bottles could 10 such machines produce in 4 minutes?\n", "id": 337, "options": ["648", "1800", "2700", "10800"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA fort had provision of food for 150 men for 45 days. After 10 days, 25 men left the fort. The number of days for which the remaining food will last, is:\n", "id": 338, "options": ["\n\n\n29\n1\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n37\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "42", "54"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n39 persons can repair a road in 12 days, working 5 hours a day. In how many days will 30 persons, working 6 hours a day, complete the work?\n", "id": 339, "options": ["10", "13", "14", "15"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\n3 pumps, working 8 hours a day, can empty a tank in 2 days. How many hours a day must 4 pumps work to empty the tank in 1 day?\n", "id": 340, "options": ["9", "10", "11", "12"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "If the cost of x metres of wire is d rupees, then what is the cost of y metres of wire at the same rate?", "id": 341, "options": ["\n\nRs.\n\nxy\n\n\n\nd\n\n", "Rs. (xd)", "Rs. (yd)", "\n\nRs.\n\nyd\n\n\n\nx\n\n"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nRunning at the same constant rate, 6 identical machines can produce a total of 270 bottles per minute. At this rate, how many bottles could 10 such machines produce in 4 minutes?\n", "id": 342, "options": ["648", "1800", "2700", "10800"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA fort had provision of food for 150 men for 45 days. After 10 days, 25 men left the fort. The number of days for which the remaining food will last, is:\n", "id": 343, "options": ["\n\n\n29\n1\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n37\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "42", "54"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n39 persons can repair a road in 12 days, working 5 hours a day. In how many days will 30 persons, working 6 hours a day, complete the work?\n", "id": 344, "options": ["10", "13", "14", "15"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\n3 pumps, working 8 hours a day, can empty a tank in 2 days. How many hours a day must 4 pumps work to empty the tank in 1 day?\n", "id": 345, "options": ["9", "10", "11", "12"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "If the cost of x metres of wire is d rupees, then what is the cost of y metres of wire at the same rate?", "id": 346, "options": ["\n\nRs.\n\nxy\n\n\n\nd\n\n", "Rs. (xd)", "Rs. (yd)", "\n\nRs.\n\nyd\n\n\n\nx\n\n"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nRunning at the same constant rate, 6 identical machines can produce a total of 270 bottles per minute. At this rate, how many bottles could 10 such machines produce in 4 minutes?\n", "id": 347, "options": ["648", "1800", "2700", "10800"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA fort had provision of food for 150 men for 45 days. After 10 days, 25 men left the fort. The number of days for which the remaining food will last, is:\n", "id": 348, "options": ["\n\n\n29\n1\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n37\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "42", "54"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n39 persons can repair a road in 12 days, working 5 hours a day. In how many days will 30 persons, working 6 hours a day, complete the work?\n", "id": 349, "options": ["10", "13", "14", "15"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Boats And Streams": [{"ans": "C", "question": "\nA boat can travel with a speed of 13 km/hr in still water. If the speed of the stream is 4 km/hr, find the time taken by the boat to go 68 km downstream.\n", "id": 350, "options": ["2 hours", "3 hours", "4 hours", "5 hours"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA man's speed with the current is 15 km/hr and the speed of the current is 2.5 km/hr. The man's speed against the current is:\n", "id": 351, "options": ["8.5 km/hr", "9 km/hr", "10 km/hr", "12.5 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA boat running upstream takes 8 hours 48 minutes to cover a certain distance, while it takes 4 hours to cover the same distance running downstream. What is the ratio between the speed of the boat and speed of the water current respectively?\n", "id": 352, "options": ["2 : 1", "3 : 2", "8 : 3", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA motorboat, whose speed in 15 km/hr in still water goes 30 km downstream and comes back in a total of 4 hours 30 minutes. The speed of the stream (in km/hr) is:\n", "id": 353, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "10"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In one hour, a boat goes 11 km/hr along the stream and 5 km/hr against the stream. The speed of the boat in still water (in km/hr) is:\r\n", "id": 354, "options": ["3 km/hr", "5 km/hr", "8 km/hr", "9 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA boat can travel with a speed of 13 km/hr in still water. If the speed of the stream is 4 km/hr, find the time taken by the boat to go 68 km downstream.\n", "id": 355, "options": ["2 hours", "3 hours", "4 hours", "5 hours"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA man's speed with the current is 15 km/hr and the speed of the current is 2.5 km/hr. The man's speed against the current is:\n", "id": 356, "options": ["8.5 km/hr", "9 km/hr", "10 km/hr", "12.5 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA boat running upstream takes 8 hours 48 minutes to cover a certain distance, while it takes 4 hours to cover the same distance running downstream. What is the ratio between the speed of the boat and speed of the water current respectively?\n", "id": 357, "options": ["2 : 1", "3 : 2", "8 : 3", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA motorboat, whose speed in 15 km/hr in still water goes 30 km downstream and comes back in a total of 4 hours 30 minutes. The speed of the stream (in km/hr) is:\n", "id": 358, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "10"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In one hour, a boat goes 11 km/hr along the stream and 5 km/hr against the stream. The speed of the boat in still water (in km/hr) is:\r\n", "id": 359, "options": ["3 km/hr", "5 km/hr", "8 km/hr", "9 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA boat can travel with a speed of 13 km/hr in still water. If the speed of the stream is 4 km/hr, find the time taken by the boat to go 68 km downstream.\n", "id": 360, "options": ["2 hours", "3 hours", "4 hours", "5 hours"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA man's speed with the current is 15 km/hr and the speed of the current is 2.5 km/hr. The man's speed against the current is:\n", "id": 361, "options": ["8.5 km/hr", "9 km/hr", "10 km/hr", "12.5 km/hr"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA boat running upstream takes 8 hours 48 minutes to cover a certain distance, while it takes 4 hours to cover the same distance running downstream. What is the ratio between the speed of the boat and speed of the water current respectively?\n", "id": 362, "options": ["2 : 1", "3 : 2", "8 : 3", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA motorboat, whose speed in 15 km/hr in still water goes 30 km downstream and comes back in a total of 4 hours 30 minutes. The speed of the stream (in km/hr) is:\n", "id": 363, "options": ["4", "5", "6", "10"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In one hour, a boat goes 11 km/hr along the stream and 5 km/hr against the stream. The speed of the boat in still water (in km/hr) is:\r\n", "id": 364, "options": ["3 km/hr", "5 km/hr", "8 km/hr", "9 km/hr"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Logarithm": [{"ans": "B", "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?", "id": 365, "options": ["log10 10 = 1", "log (2 + 3) = log (2 x 3)", "log10 1 = 0", "log (1 + 2 + 3) = log 1 + log 2 + log 3"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf log 2 = 0.3010 and log 3 = 0.4771, the value of log5 512 is:\n", "id": 366, "options": ["2.870", "2.967", "3.876", "3.912"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n\n\nlog 8\nis equal to:\n\n\nlog 8\n\n\n", "id": 367, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf log 27 = 1.431, then the value of log 9 is:\n", "id": 368, "options": ["0.934", "0.945", "0.954", "0.958"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\nIf log\na\n+\nlog\nb\n= log (a + b), then:\n\n\nb\na\n\n", "id": 369, "options": ["a + b = 1", "a - b = 1", "a = b", "a2 - b2 = 1"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?", "id": 370, "options": ["log10 10 = 1", "log (2 + 3) = log (2 x 3)", "log10 1 = 0", "log (1 + 2 + 3) = log 1 + log 2 + log 3"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf log 2 = 0.3010 and log 3 = 0.4771, the value of log5 512 is:\n", "id": 371, "options": ["2.870", "2.967", "3.876", "3.912"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n\n\nlog 8\nis equal to:\n\n\nlog 8\n\n\n", "id": 372, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf log 27 = 1.431, then the value of log 9 is:\n", "id": 373, "options": ["0.934", "0.945", "0.954", "0.958"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\nIf log\na\n+\nlog\nb\n= log (a + b), then:\n\n\nb\na\n\n", "id": 374, "options": ["a + b = 1", "a - b = 1", "a = b", "a2 - b2 = 1"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?", "id": 375, "options": ["log10 10 = 1", "log (2 + 3) = log (2 x 3)", "log10 1 = 0", "log (1 + 2 + 3) = log 1 + log 2 + log 3"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf log 2 = 0.3010 and log 3 = 0.4771, the value of log5 512 is:\n", "id": 376, "options": ["2.870", "2.967", "3.876", "3.912"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n\n\nlog 8\nis equal to:\n\n\nlog 8\n\n\n", "id": 377, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIf log 27 = 1.431, then the value of log 9 is:\n", "id": 378, "options": ["0.934", "0.945", "0.954", "0.958"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\nIf log\na\n+\nlog\nb\n= log (a + b), then:\n\n\nb\na\n\n", "id": 379, "options": ["a + b = 1", "a - b = 1", "a = b", "a2 - b2 = 1"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Stocks And Shares": [{"ans": "B", "question": "\nIn order to obtain an income of Rs. 650 from 10% stock at Rs. 96, one must make an investment of:\n", "id": 380, "options": ["Rs. 3100", "Rs. 6240", "Rs. 6500", "Rs. 9600"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA man bought 20 shares of Rs. 50 at 5 discount, the rate of dividend being 13. The rate of interest obtained is:\n", "id": 381, "options": ["\n\n\n12\n1\n%\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n13\n1\n%\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "15%", "\n\n\n16\n2\n%\n\n\n3\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nWhich is better investment:  11% stock at 143 \u00a0or\u00a0 9% stock at 117?\n", "id": 382, "options": ["11% stock at 143", "\n\n\n9\n3\n% stock at 117\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "Both are equally good", "Cannot be compared, as the total amount of investment is not given."]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA man buys Rs. 20 shares paying 9% dividend. The man wants to have an interest of 12% on his money. The market value of each share is:\n", "id": 383, "options": ["Rs. 12", "Rs. 15", "Rs. 18", "Rs. 21"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nBy investing in 16% stock at 64, one earns Rs. 1500. The investment made is:\n", "id": 384, "options": ["Rs. 5640", "Rs. 5760", "Rs. 7500", "Rs. 9600"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nIn order to obtain an income of Rs. 650 from 10% stock at Rs. 96, one must make an investment of:\n", "id": 385, "options": ["Rs. 3100", "Rs. 6240", "Rs. 6500", "Rs. 9600"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA man bought 20 shares of Rs. 50 at 5 discount, the rate of dividend being 13. The rate of interest obtained is:\n", "id": 386, "options": ["\n\n\n12\n1\n%\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n13\n1\n%\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "15%", "\n\n\n16\n2\n%\n\n\n3\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nWhich is better investment:  11% stock at 143 \u00a0or\u00a0 9% stock at 117?\n", "id": 387, "options": ["11% stock at 143", "\n\n\n9\n3\n% stock at 117\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "Both are equally good", "Cannot be compared, as the total amount of investment is not given."]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA man buys Rs. 20 shares paying 9% dividend. The man wants to have an interest of 12% on his money. The market value of each share is:\n", "id": 388, "options": ["Rs. 12", "Rs. 15", "Rs. 18", "Rs. 21"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nBy investing in 16% stock at 64, one earns Rs. 1500. The investment made is:\n", "id": 389, "options": ["Rs. 5640", "Rs. 5760", "Rs. 7500", "Rs. 9600"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nIn order to obtain an income of Rs. 650 from 10% stock at Rs. 96, one must make an investment of:\n", "id": 390, "options": ["Rs. 3100", "Rs. 6240", "Rs. 6500", "Rs. 9600"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA man bought 20 shares of Rs. 50 at 5 discount, the rate of dividend being 13. The rate of interest obtained is:\n", "id": 391, "options": ["\n\n\n12\n1\n%\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n13\n1\n%\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "15%", "\n\n\n16\n2\n%\n\n\n3\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nWhich is better investment:  11% stock at 143 \u00a0or\u00a0 9% stock at 117?\n", "id": 392, "options": ["11% stock at 143", "\n\n\n9\n3\n% stock at 117\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "Both are equally good", "Cannot be compared, as the total amount of investment is not given."]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA man buys Rs. 20 shares paying 9% dividend. The man wants to have an interest of 12% on his money. The market value of each share is:\n", "id": 393, "options": ["Rs. 12", "Rs. 15", "Rs. 18", "Rs. 21"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nBy investing in 16% stock at 64, one earns Rs. 1500. The investment made is:\n", "id": 394, "options": ["Rs. 5640", "Rs. 5760", "Rs. 7500", "Rs. 9600"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"True Discount": [{"ans": "A", "question": "\nA man purchased a cow for Rs. 3000 and sold it the same day for Rs. 3600, allowing the buyer a credit of 2 years. If the rate of interest be 10% per annum, then the man has a gain of:\n", "id": 395, "options": ["0%", "5%", "7.5%", "10%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe true discount on Rs. 2562 due 4 months hence is Rs. 122. The rate percent is:\n", "id": 396, "options": ["12%", "\n\n\n13\n1\n%\n\n\n3\n\n\n", "15%", "14%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA trader owes a merchant Rs. 10,028 due 1 year hence. The trader wants to settle the account after 3 months. If the rate of interest 12% per annum, how much cash should he pay?\n", "id": 397, "options": ["Rs. 9025.20", "Rs. 9200", "Rs. 9600", "Rs. 9560"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA man wants to sell his scooter. There are two offers, one at Rs. 12,000 cash and the other a credit of Rs. 12,880 to be paid after 8 months, money being at 18% per annum. Which is the better offer?\n", "id": 398, "options": ["Rs. 12,000 in cash", "s. 12,880 at credit", "Both are equally good"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf Rs. 10 be allowed as true discount on a bill of Rs. 110 due at the end of a certain time, then the discount allowed on the same sum due at the end of double the time is:\n", "id": 399, "options": ["Rs. 20", "Rs. 21.81", "Rs. 22", "Rs. 18.33"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA man purchased a cow for Rs. 3000 and sold it the same day for Rs. 3600, allowing the buyer a credit of 2 years. If the rate of interest be 10% per annum, then the man has a gain of:\n", "id": 400, "options": ["0%", "5%", "7.5%", "10%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe true discount on Rs. 2562 due 4 months hence is Rs. 122. The rate percent is:\n", "id": 401, "options": ["12%", "\n\n\n13\n1\n%\n\n\n3\n\n\n", "15%", "14%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA trader owes a merchant Rs. 10,028 due 1 year hence. The trader wants to settle the account after 3 months. If the rate of interest 12% per annum, how much cash should he pay?\n", "id": 402, "options": ["Rs. 9025.20", "Rs. 9200", "Rs. 9600", "Rs. 9560"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA man wants to sell his scooter. There are two offers, one at Rs. 12,000 cash and the other a credit of Rs. 12,880 to be paid after 8 months, money being at 18% per annum. Which is the better offer?\n", "id": 403, "options": ["Rs. 12,000 in cash", "s. 12,880 at credit", "Both are equally good"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf Rs. 10 be allowed as true discount on a bill of Rs. 110 due at the end of a certain time, then the discount allowed on the same sum due at the end of double the time is:\n", "id": 404, "options": ["Rs. 20", "Rs. 21.81", "Rs. 22", "Rs. 18.33"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA man purchased a cow for Rs. 3000 and sold it the same day for Rs. 3600, allowing the buyer a credit of 2 years. If the rate of interest be 10% per annum, then the man has a gain of:\n", "id": 405, "options": ["0%", "5%", "7.5%", "10%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe true discount on Rs. 2562 due 4 months hence is Rs. 122. The rate percent is:\n", "id": 406, "options": ["12%", "\n\n\n13\n1\n%\n\n\n3\n\n\n", "15%", "14%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA trader owes a merchant Rs. 10,028 due 1 year hence. The trader wants to settle the account after 3 months. If the rate of interest 12% per annum, how much cash should he pay?\n", "id": 407, "options": ["Rs. 9025.20", "Rs. 9200", "Rs. 9600", "Rs. 9560"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA man wants to sell his scooter. There are two offers, one at Rs. 12,000 cash and the other a credit of Rs. 12,880 to be paid after 8 months, money being at 18% per annum. Which is the better offer?\n", "id": 408, "options": ["Rs. 12,000 in cash", "s. 12,880 at credit", "Both are equally good"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf Rs. 10 be allowed as true discount on a bill of Rs. 110 due at the end of a certain time, then the discount allowed on the same sum due at the end of double the time is:\n", "id": 409, "options": ["Rs. 20", "Rs. 21.81", "Rs. 22", "Rs. 18.33"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Odd Man Out And Series": [{"ans": "C", "question": "3, 5, 11, 14, 17, 21", "id": 410, "options": ["21", "17", "14", "3"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n8, 27, 64, 100, 125, 216, 343\n", "id": 411, "options": ["27", "100", "125", "343"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n10, 25, 45, 54, 60, 75, 80\n", "id": 412, "options": ["10", "45", "54", "75"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "396, 462, 572, 427, 671, 264", "id": 413, "options": ["396", "427", "671", "264"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n6, 9, 15, 21, 24, 28, 30\n", "id": 414, "options": ["28", "21", "24", "30"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "3, 5, 11, 14, 17, 21", "id": 415, "options": ["21", "17", "14", "3"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n8, 27, 64, 100, 125, 216, 343\n", "id": 416, "options": ["27", "100", "125", "343"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n10, 25, 45, 54, 60, 75, 80\n", "id": 417, "options": ["10", "45", "54", "75"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "396, 462, 572, 427, 671, 264", "id": 418, "options": ["396", "427", "671", "264"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n6, 9, 15, 21, 24, 28, 30\n", "id": 419, "options": ["28", "21", "24", "30"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "3, 5, 11, 14, 17, 21", "id": 420, "options": ["21", "17", "14", "3"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n8, 27, 64, 100, 125, 216, 343\n", "id": 421, "options": ["27", "100", "125", "343"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\n10, 25, 45, 54, 60, 75, 80\n", "id": 422, "options": ["10", "45", "54", "75"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "396, 462, 572, 427, 671, 264", "id": 423, "options": ["396", "427", "671", "264"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n6, 9, 15, 21, 24, 28, 30\n", "id": 424, "options": ["28", "21", "24", "30"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Time And Distance": [{"ans": "B", "question": "A person crosses a 600 m long street in 5 minutes. What is his speed in km per hour?", "id": 425, "options": ["3.6", "7.2", "8.4", "10"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "An aeroplane covers a certain distance at a speed of 240 kmph in 5 hours. To cover the same distance in 1 hours, it must travel at a speed of:", "id": 426, "options": ["300 kmph", "360 kmph", "600 kmph", "720 kmph"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf a person walks at 14 km/hr instead of 10 km/hr, he would have walked 20 km more. The actual distance travelled by him is:\n", "id": 427, "options": ["50 km", "56 km", "70 km", "80 km"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA train can travel 50% faster than a car. Both start from point A at the same time and reach point B 75 kms away from A at the same time. On the way, however, the train lost about 12.5 minutes while stopping at the stations. The speed of the car is:\n", "id": 428, "options": ["100 kmph", "110 kmph", "120 kmph", "130 kmph"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Excluding stoppages, the speed of a bus is 54 kmph and including stoppages, it is 45 kmph. For how many minutes does the bus stop per hour?", "id": 429, "options": ["9", "10", "12", "20"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A person crosses a 600 m long street in 5 minutes. What is his speed in km per hour?", "id": 430, "options": ["3.6", "7.2", "8.4", "10"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "An aeroplane covers a certain distance at a speed of 240 kmph in 5 hours. To cover the same distance in 1 hours, it must travel at a speed of:", "id": 431, "options": ["300 kmph", "360 kmph", "600 kmph", "720 kmph"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf a person walks at 14 km/hr instead of 10 km/hr, he would have walked 20 km more. The actual distance travelled by him is:\n", "id": 432, "options": ["50 km", "56 km", "70 km", "80 km"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA train can travel 50% faster than a car. Both start from point A at the same time and reach point B 75 kms away from A at the same time. On the way, however, the train lost about 12.5 minutes while stopping at the stations. The speed of the car is:\n", "id": 433, "options": ["100 kmph", "110 kmph", "120 kmph", "130 kmph"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Excluding stoppages, the speed of a bus is 54 kmph and including stoppages, it is 45 kmph. For how many minutes does the bus stop per hour?", "id": 434, "options": ["9", "10", "12", "20"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A person crosses a 600 m long street in 5 minutes. What is his speed in km per hour?", "id": 435, "options": ["3.6", "7.2", "8.4", "10"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "An aeroplane covers a certain distance at a speed of 240 kmph in 5 hours. To cover the same distance in 1 hours, it must travel at a speed of:", "id": 436, "options": ["300 kmph", "360 kmph", "600 kmph", "720 kmph"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIf a person walks at 14 km/hr instead of 10 km/hr, he would have walked 20 km more. The actual distance travelled by him is:\n", "id": 437, "options": ["50 km", "56 km", "70 km", "80 km"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA train can travel 50% faster than a car. Both start from point A at the same time and reach point B 75 kms away from A at the same time. On the way, however, the train lost about 12.5 minutes while stopping at the stations. The speed of the car is:\n", "id": 438, "options": ["100 kmph", "110 kmph", "120 kmph", "130 kmph"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Excluding stoppages, the speed of a bus is 54 kmph and including stoppages, it is 45 kmph. For how many minutes does the bus stop per hour?", "id": 439, "options": ["9", "10", "12", "20"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Time And Work": [{"ans": "D", "question": "A can do a work in 15 days and B in 20 days. If they work on it together for 4 days, then the fraction of the work that is left is :", "id": 440, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n10\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n15\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can lay railway track between two given stations in 16 days and B can do the same job in 12 days. With help of C, they did the job in 4 days only. Then, C alone can do the job in:", "id": 441, "options": ["\n\n\n9\n1\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n2\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n3\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "10"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C can do a piece of work in 20, 30 and 60 days respectively. In how many days can A do the work if he is assisted by B and C on every third day?\n", "id": 442, "options": ["12 days", "15 days", "16 days", "18 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A is thrice as good as workman as B and therefore is able to finish a job in 60 days less than B. Working together, they can do it in:\r\n", "id": 443, "options": ["20 days", "\n\n22\n1\ndays\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "25 days", "30 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA alone can do a piece of work in 6 days and B alone in 8 days. A and B undertook to do it for Rs. 3200. With the help of C, they completed the work in 3 days. How much is to be paid to C?\n", "id": 444, "options": ["Rs. 375", "Rs. 400", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 800"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A can do a work in 15 days and B in 20 days. If they work on it together for 4 days, then the fraction of the work that is left is :", "id": 445, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n10\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n15\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can lay railway track between two given stations in 16 days and B can do the same job in 12 days. With help of C, they did the job in 4 days only. Then, C alone can do the job in:", "id": 446, "options": ["\n\n\n9\n1\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n2\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n3\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "10"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C can do a piece of work in 20, 30 and 60 days respectively. In how many days can A do the work if he is assisted by B and C on every third day?\n", "id": 447, "options": ["12 days", "15 days", "16 days", "18 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A is thrice as good as workman as B and therefore is able to finish a job in 60 days less than B. Working together, they can do it in:\r\n", "id": 448, "options": ["20 days", "\n\n22\n1\ndays\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "25 days", "30 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA alone can do a piece of work in 6 days and B alone in 8 days. A and B undertook to do it for Rs. 3200. With the help of C, they completed the work in 3 days. How much is to be paid to C?\n", "id": 449, "options": ["Rs. 375", "Rs. 400", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 800"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A can do a work in 15 days and B in 20 days. If they work on it together for 4 days, then the fraction of the work that is left is :", "id": 450, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n10\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n15\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can lay railway track between two given stations in 16 days and B can do the same job in 12 days. With help of C, they did the job in 4 days only. Then, C alone can do the job in:", "id": 451, "options": ["\n\n\n9\n1\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n2\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n3\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "10"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C can do a piece of work in 20, 30 and 60 days respectively. In how many days can A do the work if he is assisted by B and C on every third day?\n", "id": 452, "options": ["12 days", "15 days", "16 days", "18 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A is thrice as good as workman as B and therefore is able to finish a job in 60 days less than B. Working together, they can do it in:\r\n", "id": 453, "options": ["20 days", "\n\n22\n1\ndays\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "25 days", "30 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA alone can do a piece of work in 6 days and B alone in 8 days. A and B undertook to do it for Rs. 3200. With the help of C, they completed the work in 3 days. How much is to be paid to C?\n", "id": 454, "options": ["Rs. 375", "Rs. 400", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 800"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A can do a work in 15 days and B in 20 days. If they work on it together for 4 days, then the fraction of the work that is left is :", "id": 455, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n10\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n15\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can lay railway track between two given stations in 16 days and B can do the same job in 12 days. With help of C, they did the job in 4 days only. Then, C alone can do the job in:", "id": 456, "options": ["\n\n\n9\n1\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n2\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n3\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "10"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C can do a piece of work in 20, 30 and 60 days respectively. In how many days can A do the work if he is assisted by B and C on every third day?\n", "id": 457, "options": ["12 days", "15 days", "16 days", "18 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A is thrice as good as workman as B and therefore is able to finish a job in 60 days less than B. Working together, they can do it in:\r\n", "id": 458, "options": ["20 days", "\n\n22\n1\ndays\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "25 days", "30 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA alone can do a piece of work in 6 days and B alone in 8 days. A and B undertook to do it for Rs. 3200. With the help of C, they completed the work in 3 days. How much is to be paid to C?\n", "id": 459, "options": ["Rs. 375", "Rs. 400", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 800"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A can do a work in 15 days and B in 20 days. If they work on it together for 4 days, then the fraction of the work that is left is :", "id": 460, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n10\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n15\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can lay railway track between two given stations in 16 days and B can do the same job in 12 days. With help of C, they did the job in 4 days only. Then, C alone can do the job in:", "id": 461, "options": ["\n\n\n9\n1\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n2\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n3\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "10"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C can do a piece of work in 20, 30 and 60 days respectively. In how many days can A do the work if he is assisted by B and C on every third day?\n", "id": 462, "options": ["12 days", "15 days", "16 days", "18 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A is thrice as good as workman as B and therefore is able to finish a job in 60 days less than B. Working together, they can do it in:\r\n", "id": 463, "options": ["20 days", "\n\n22\n1\ndays\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "25 days", "30 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA alone can do a piece of work in 6 days and B alone in 8 days. A and B undertook to do it for Rs. 3200. With the help of C, they completed the work in 3 days. How much is to be paid to C?\n", "id": 464, "options": ["Rs. 375", "Rs. 400", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 800"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A can do a work in 15 days and B in 20 days. If they work on it together for 4 days, then the fraction of the work that is left is :", "id": 465, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n10\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n15\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can lay railway track between two given stations in 16 days and B can do the same job in 12 days. With help of C, they did the job in 4 days only. Then, C alone can do the job in:", "id": 466, "options": ["\n\n\n9\n1\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n2\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n3\ndays\n\n\n5\n\n\n", "10"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C can do a piece of work in 20, 30 and 60 days respectively. In how many days can A do the work if he is assisted by B and C on every third day?\n", "id": 467, "options": ["12 days", "15 days", "16 days", "18 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A is thrice as good as workman as B and therefore is able to finish a job in 60 days less than B. Working together, they can do it in:\r\n", "id": 468, "options": ["20 days", "\n\n22\n1\ndays\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "25 days", "30 days"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA alone can do a piece of work in 6 days and B alone in 8 days. A and B undertook to do it for Rs. 3200. With the help of C, they completed the work in 3 days. How much is to be paid to C?\n", "id": 469, "options": ["Rs. 375", "Rs. 400", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 800"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Compound Interest": [{"ans": "B", "question": "A bank offers 5% compound interest calculated on half-yearly basis. A customer deposits Rs. 1600 each on 1st January and 1st July of a year. At the end of the year, the amount he would have gained by way of interest is:\r\n", "id": 470, "options": ["Rs. 120", "Rs. 121", "Rs. 122", "Rs. 123"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe difference between simple and compound interests compounded annually on a certain sum of money for 2 years at 4% per annum is Re. 1. The sum (in Rs.) is:\n", "id": 471, "options": ["625", "630", "640", "650"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThere is 60% increase in an amount in 6 years at simple interest. What will be the compound interest of Rs. 12,000 after 3 years at the same rate?\n", "id": 472, "options": ["Rs. 2160", "Rs. 3120", "Rs. 3972", "Rs. 6240", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the difference between the compound interests on Rs. 5000 for 1 years at 4% per annum compounded yearly and half-yearly?\r\n", "id": 473, "options": ["Rs. 2.04", "Rs. 3.06", "Rs. 4.80", "Rs. 8.30"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe compound interest on Rs. 30,000 at 7% per annum is Rs. 4347. The period (in years) is:\n", "id": 474, "options": ["2", "\n\n\n2\n1\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "3", "4"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A bank offers 5% compound interest calculated on half-yearly basis. A customer deposits Rs. 1600 each on 1st January and 1st July of a year. At the end of the year, the amount he would have gained by way of interest is:\r\n", "id": 475, "options": ["Rs. 120", "Rs. 121", "Rs. 122", "Rs. 123"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe difference between simple and compound interests compounded annually on a certain sum of money for 2 years at 4% per annum is Re. 1. The sum (in Rs.) is:\n", "id": 476, "options": ["625", "630", "640", "650"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThere is 60% increase in an amount in 6 years at simple interest. What will be the compound interest of Rs. 12,000 after 3 years at the same rate?\n", "id": 477, "options": ["Rs. 2160", "Rs. 3120", "Rs. 3972", "Rs. 6240", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the difference between the compound interests on Rs. 5000 for 1 years at 4% per annum compounded yearly and half-yearly?\r\n", "id": 478, "options": ["Rs. 2.04", "Rs. 3.06", "Rs. 4.80", "Rs. 8.30"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe compound interest on Rs. 30,000 at 7% per annum is Rs. 4347. The period (in years) is:\n", "id": 479, "options": ["2", "\n\n\n2\n1\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "3", "4"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A bank offers 5% compound interest calculated on half-yearly basis. A customer deposits Rs. 1600 each on 1st January and 1st July of a year. At the end of the year, the amount he would have gained by way of interest is:\r\n", "id": 480, "options": ["Rs. 120", "Rs. 121", "Rs. 122", "Rs. 123"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe difference between simple and compound interests compounded annually on a certain sum of money for 2 years at 4% per annum is Re. 1. The sum (in Rs.) is:\n", "id": 481, "options": ["625", "630", "640", "650"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThere is 60% increase in an amount in 6 years at simple interest. What will be the compound interest of Rs. 12,000 after 3 years at the same rate?\n", "id": 482, "options": ["Rs. 2160", "Rs. 3120", "Rs. 3972", "Rs. 6240", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "What is the difference between the compound interests on Rs. 5000 for 1 years at 4% per annum compounded yearly and half-yearly?\r\n", "id": 483, "options": ["Rs. 2.04", "Rs. 3.06", "Rs. 4.80", "Rs. 8.30"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe compound interest on Rs. 30,000 at 7% per annum is Rs. 4347. The period (in years) is:\n", "id": 484, "options": ["2", "\n\n\n2\n1\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "3", "4"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Partnership": [{"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B invest in a business in the ratio 3 : 2. If 5% of the total profit goes to charity and A's share is Rs. 855, the total profit is:\n", "id": 485, "options": ["Rs. 1425", "Rs. 1500", "Rs. 1537.50", "Rs. 1576"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C jointly thought of engaging themselves in a business venture. It was agreed that A would invest Rs. 6500 for 6 months, B, Rs. 8400 for 5 months and C, Rs. 10,000 for 3 months. A wants to be the working member for which, he was to receive 5% of the profits. The profit earned was Rs. 7400. Calculate the share of B in the profit.\n", "id": 486, "options": ["Rs. 1900", "Rs. 2660", "Rs. 2800", "Rs. 2840"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA, B and C enter into a partnership in the ratio  :  : . After 4 months, A increases his share 50%. If the total profit at the end of one year be Rs. 21,600, then B's share in the profit is:\n", "id": 487, "options": ["Rs. 2100", "Rs. 2400", "Rs. 3600", "Rs. 4000"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A, B, C subscribe Rs. 50,000 for a business. A subscribes Rs. 4000 more than B and B Rs. 5000 more than C. Out of a total profit of Rs. 35,000, A receives:\r\n", "id": 488, "options": ["Rs. 8400", "Rs. 11,900", "Rs. 13,600", "Rs. 14,700"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Three partners shared the profit in a business in the ratio 5 : 7 : 8. They had partnered for 14 months, 8 months and 7 months respectively. What was the ratio of their investments?\r\n", "id": 489, "options": ["5 : 7 : 8", "20 : 49 : 64", "38 : 28 : 21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B invest in a business in the ratio 3 : 2. If 5% of the total profit goes to charity and A's share is Rs. 855, the total profit is:\n", "id": 490, "options": ["Rs. 1425", "Rs. 1500", "Rs. 1537.50", "Rs. 1576"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C jointly thought of engaging themselves in a business venture. It was agreed that A would invest Rs. 6500 for 6 months, B, Rs. 8400 for 5 months and C, Rs. 10,000 for 3 months. A wants to be the working member for which, he was to receive 5% of the profits. The profit earned was Rs. 7400. Calculate the share of B in the profit.\n", "id": 491, "options": ["Rs. 1900", "Rs. 2660", "Rs. 2800", "Rs. 2840"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA, B and C enter into a partnership in the ratio  :  : . After 4 months, A increases his share 50%. If the total profit at the end of one year be Rs. 21,600, then B's share in the profit is:\n", "id": 492, "options": ["Rs. 2100", "Rs. 2400", "Rs. 3600", "Rs. 4000"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A, B, C subscribe Rs. 50,000 for a business. A subscribes Rs. 4000 more than B and B Rs. 5000 more than C. Out of a total profit of Rs. 35,000, A receives:\r\n", "id": 493, "options": ["Rs. 8400", "Rs. 11,900", "Rs. 13,600", "Rs. 14,700"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Three partners shared the profit in a business in the ratio 5 : 7 : 8. They had partnered for 14 months, 8 months and 7 months respectively. What was the ratio of their investments?\r\n", "id": 494, "options": ["5 : 7 : 8", "20 : 49 : 64", "38 : 28 : 21", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B invest in a business in the ratio 3 : 2. If 5% of the total profit goes to charity and A's share is Rs. 855, the total profit is:\n", "id": 495, "options": ["Rs. 1425", "Rs. 1500", "Rs. 1537.50", "Rs. 1576"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA, B and C jointly thought of engaging themselves in a business venture. It was agreed that A would invest Rs. 6500 for 6 months, B, Rs. 8400 for 5 months and C, Rs. 10,000 for 3 months. A wants to be the working member for which, he was to receive 5% of the profits. The profit earned was Rs. 7400. Calculate the share of B in the profit.\n", "id": 496, "options": ["Rs. 1900", "Rs. 2660", "Rs. 2800", "Rs. 2840"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA, B and C enter into a partnership in the ratio  :  : . After 4 months, A increases his share 50%. If the total profit at the end of one year be Rs. 21,600, then B's share in the profit is:\n", "id": 497, "options": ["Rs. 2100", "Rs. 2400", "Rs. 3600", "Rs. 4000"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A, B, C subscribe Rs. 50,000 for a business. A subscribes Rs. 4000 more than B and B Rs. 5000 more than C. Out of a total profit of Rs. 35,000, A receives:\r\n", "id": 498, "options": ["Rs. 8400", "Rs. 11,900", "Rs. 13,600", "Rs. 14,700"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "Three partners shared the profit in a business in the ratio 5 : 7 : 8. They had partnered for 14 months, 8 months and 7 months respectively. What was the ratio of their investments?\r\n", "id": 499, "options": ["5 : 7 : 8", "20 : 49 : 64", "38 : 28 : 21", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Problems On Ages": [{"ans": "A", "question": "\nFather is aged three times more than his son Ronit. After 8 years, he would be two and a half times of Ronit's age. After further 8 years,  how many times would he be of Ronit's age?\n", "id": 500, "options": ["2 times", "\n\n\n2\u00a0\n1\ntimes\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\u00a0\n3\ntimes\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "3 times"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe sum of ages of 5 children born at the intervals of 3 years each is 50 years. What is the age of the youngest child?\n", "id": 501, "options": ["4 years", "8 years", "10 years", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA father said to his son, \"I was as old as you are at the present at the time of your birth\". If the father's age is 38 years now, the son's age five years back was:\n", "id": 502, "options": ["14 years", "19 years", "33 years", "38 years"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA is two years older than B who is twice as old as C. If the total of the ages of A, B and C be 27, the how old is B?\n", "id": 503, "options": ["7", "8", "9", "10", "11"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Present ages of Sameer and Anand are in the ratio of 5 : 4 respectively. Three years hence, the ratio of their ages will become 11 : 9 respectively. What is Anand's present age in years?", "id": 504, "options": ["24", "27", "40", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nFather is aged three times more than his son Ronit. After 8 years, he would be two and a half times of Ronit's age. After further 8 years,  how many times would he be of Ronit's age?\n", "id": 505, "options": ["2 times", "\n\n\n2\u00a0\n1\ntimes\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\u00a0\n3\ntimes\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "3 times"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe sum of ages of 5 children born at the intervals of 3 years each is 50 years. What is the age of the youngest child?\n", "id": 506, "options": ["4 years", "8 years", "10 years", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA father said to his son, \"I was as old as you are at the present at the time of your birth\". If the father's age is 38 years now, the son's age five years back was:\n", "id": 507, "options": ["14 years", "19 years", "33 years", "38 years"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA is two years older than B who is twice as old as C. If the total of the ages of A, B and C be 27, the how old is B?\n", "id": 508, "options": ["7", "8", "9", "10", "11"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Present ages of Sameer and Anand are in the ratio of 5 : 4 respectively. Three years hence, the ratio of their ages will become 11 : 9 respectively. What is Anand's present age in years?", "id": 509, "options": ["24", "27", "40", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nFather is aged three times more than his son Ronit. After 8 years, he would be two and a half times of Ronit's age. After further 8 years,  how many times would he be of Ronit's age?\n", "id": 510, "options": ["2 times", "\n\n\n2\u00a0\n1\ntimes\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\u00a0\n3\ntimes\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "3 times"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe sum of ages of 5 children born at the intervals of 3 years each is 50 years. What is the age of the youngest child?\n", "id": 511, "options": ["4 years", "8 years", "10 years", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA father said to his son, \"I was as old as you are at the present at the time of your birth\". If the father's age is 38 years now, the son's age five years back was:\n", "id": 512, "options": ["14 years", "19 years", "33 years", "38 years"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nA is two years older than B who is twice as old as C. If the total of the ages of A, B and C be 27, the how old is B?\n", "id": 513, "options": ["7", "8", "9", "10", "11"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "Present ages of Sameer and Anand are in the ratio of 5 : 4 respectively. Three years hence, the ratio of their ages will become 11 : 9 respectively. What is Anand's present age in years?", "id": 514, "options": ["24", "27", "40", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Clock": [{"ans": "D", "question": "\nAn accurate clock shows 8 o'clock in the morning. Through how may degrees will the hour hand rotate when the clock shows 2 o'clock in the afternoon? \n", "id": 515, "options": ["144\u00ba", "150\u00ba", "168\u00ba", "180\u00ba"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe reflex angle between the hands of a clock at 10.25 is:\n", "id": 516, "options": ["180\u00ba", "\n\n\n192\n1\n\u00ba\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "195\u00ba", "\n\n\n197\n1\n\u00ba\n\n\n2\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA clock is started at noon. By 10 minutes past 5, the hour hand has turned through:\n", "id": 517, "options": ["145\u00ba", "150\u00ba", "155\u00ba", "160\u00ba"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA watch which gains 5 seconds in 3 minutes was set right at 7 a.m. In the afternoon of the same day, when the watch indicated quarter past 4 o'clock, the true time is:\n", "id": 518, "options": ["\n\n\n59\n7\nmin. past 3\n\n\n12\n\n\n", "4 p.m.", "\n\n\n58\n7\nmin. past 3\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n3\nmin. past 4\n\n\n11\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How much does a watch lose per day, if its hands coincide every 64 minutes?", "id": 519, "options": ["\n\n32\n8\nmin.\n\n\n11\n\n", "\n\n36\n5\nmin.\n\n\n11\n\n", "90 min.", "96 min."]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nAn accurate clock shows 8 o'clock in the morning. Through how may degrees will the hour hand rotate when the clock shows 2 o'clock in the afternoon? \n", "id": 520, "options": ["144\u00ba", "150\u00ba", "168\u00ba", "180\u00ba"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe reflex angle between the hands of a clock at 10.25 is:\n", "id": 521, "options": ["180\u00ba", "\n\n\n192\n1\n\u00ba\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "195\u00ba", "\n\n\n197\n1\n\u00ba\n\n\n2\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA clock is started at noon. By 10 minutes past 5, the hour hand has turned through:\n", "id": 522, "options": ["145\u00ba", "150\u00ba", "155\u00ba", "160\u00ba"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA watch which gains 5 seconds in 3 minutes was set right at 7 a.m. In the afternoon of the same day, when the watch indicated quarter past 4 o'clock, the true time is:\n", "id": 523, "options": ["\n\n\n59\n7\nmin. past 3\n\n\n12\n\n\n", "4 p.m.", "\n\n\n58\n7\nmin. past 3\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n3\nmin. past 4\n\n\n11\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How much does a watch lose per day, if its hands coincide every 64 minutes?", "id": 524, "options": ["\n\n32\n8\nmin.\n\n\n11\n\n", "\n\n36\n5\nmin.\n\n\n11\n\n", "90 min.", "96 min."]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nAn accurate clock shows 8 o'clock in the morning. Through how may degrees will the hour hand rotate when the clock shows 2 o'clock in the afternoon? \n", "id": 525, "options": ["144\u00ba", "150\u00ba", "168\u00ba", "180\u00ba"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe reflex angle between the hands of a clock at 10.25 is:\n", "id": 526, "options": ["180\u00ba", "\n\n\n192\n1\n\u00ba\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "195\u00ba", "\n\n\n197\n1\n\u00ba\n\n\n2\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA clock is started at noon. By 10 minutes past 5, the hour hand has turned through:\n", "id": 527, "options": ["145\u00ba", "150\u00ba", "155\u00ba", "160\u00ba"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA watch which gains 5 seconds in 3 minutes was set right at 7 a.m. In the afternoon of the same day, when the watch indicated quarter past 4 o'clock, the true time is:\n", "id": 528, "options": ["\n\n\n59\n7\nmin. past 3\n\n\n12\n\n\n", "4 p.m.", "\n\n\n58\n7\nmin. past 3\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n3\nmin. past 4\n\n\n11\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How much does a watch lose per day, if its hands coincide every 64 minutes?", "id": 529, "options": ["\n\n32\n8\nmin.\n\n\n11\n\n", "\n\n36\n5\nmin.\n\n\n11\n\n", "90 min.", "96 min."]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nAn accurate clock shows 8 o'clock in the morning. Through how may degrees will the hour hand rotate when the clock shows 2 o'clock in the afternoon? \n", "id": 530, "options": ["144\u00ba", "150\u00ba", "168\u00ba", "180\u00ba"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThe reflex angle between the hands of a clock at 10.25 is:\n", "id": 531, "options": ["180\u00ba", "\n\n\n192\n1\n\u00ba\n\n\n2\n\n\n", "195\u00ba", "\n\n\n197\n1\n\u00ba\n\n\n2\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA clock is started at noon. By 10 minutes past 5, the hour hand has turned through:\n", "id": 532, "options": ["145\u00ba", "150\u00ba", "155\u00ba", "160\u00ba"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA watch which gains 5 seconds in 3 minutes was set right at 7 a.m. In the afternoon of the same day, when the watch indicated quarter past 4 o'clock, the true time is:\n", "id": 533, "options": ["\n\n\n59\n7\nmin. past 3\n\n\n12\n\n\n", "4 p.m.", "\n\n\n58\n7\nmin. past 3\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n3\nmin. past 4\n\n\n11\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "How much does a watch lose per day, if its hands coincide every 64 minutes?", "id": 534, "options": ["\n\n32\n8\nmin.\n\n\n11\n\n", "\n\n36\n5\nmin.\n\n\n11\n\n", "90 min.", "96 min."]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Area": [{"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe ratio between the length and the breadth of a rectangular park is 3 : 2. If a man cycling along the boundary of the park at the speed of 12 km/hr completes one round in 8 minutes, then the area of the park (in sq. m) is:\n", "id": 535, "options": ["15360", "153600", "30720", "307200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nAn error 2% in excess is made while measuring the side of a square. The percentage of error in the calculated area of the square is:\n", "id": 536, "options": ["2%", "2.02%", "4%", "4.04%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe ratio between the perimeter and the breadth of a rectangle is 5 : 1. If the area of the rectangle is 216 sq. cm, what is the length of the rectangle?\n", "id": 537, "options": ["16 cm", "18 cm", "24 cm", "Data inadequate", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "The percentage increase in the area of a rectangle, if each of its sides is increased by 20% is:", "id": 538, "options": ["40%", "42%", "44%", "46%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA rectangular park 60 m long and 40 m wide has two concrete crossroads running in the middle of the park and rest of the park has been used as a lawn. If the area of the lawn is 2109 sq. m, then what is the width of the road?\n", "id": 539, "options": ["2.91 m", "3 m", "5.82 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe ratio between the length and the breadth of a rectangular park is 3 : 2. If a man cycling along the boundary of the park at the speed of 12 km/hr completes one round in 8 minutes, then the area of the park (in sq. m) is:\n", "id": 540, "options": ["15360", "153600", "30720", "307200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nAn error 2% in excess is made while measuring the side of a square. The percentage of error in the calculated area of the square is:\n", "id": 541, "options": ["2%", "2.02%", "4%", "4.04%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe ratio between the perimeter and the breadth of a rectangle is 5 : 1. If the area of the rectangle is 216 sq. cm, what is the length of the rectangle?\n", "id": 542, "options": ["16 cm", "18 cm", "24 cm", "Data inadequate", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "The percentage increase in the area of a rectangle, if each of its sides is increased by 20% is:", "id": 543, "options": ["40%", "42%", "44%", "46%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA rectangular park 60 m long and 40 m wide has two concrete crossroads running in the middle of the park and rest of the park has been used as a lawn. If the area of the lawn is 2109 sq. m, then what is the width of the road?\n", "id": 544, "options": ["2.91 m", "3 m", "5.82 m", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe ratio between the length and the breadth of a rectangular park is 3 : 2. If a man cycling along the boundary of the park at the speed of 12 km/hr completes one round in 8 minutes, then the area of the park (in sq. m) is:\n", "id": 545, "options": ["15360", "153600", "30720", "307200"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nAn error 2% in excess is made while measuring the side of a square. The percentage of error in the calculated area of the square is:\n", "id": 546, "options": ["2%", "2.02%", "4%", "4.04%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe ratio between the perimeter and the breadth of a rectangle is 5 : 1. If the area of the rectangle is 216 sq. cm, what is the length of the rectangle?\n", "id": 547, "options": ["16 cm", "18 cm", "24 cm", "Data inadequate", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "The percentage increase in the area of a rectangle, if each of its sides is increased by 20% is:", "id": 548, "options": ["40%", "42%", "44%", "46%"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA rectangular park 60 m long and 40 m wide has two concrete crossroads running in the middle of the park and rest of the park has been used as a lawn. If the area of the lawn is 2109 sq. m, then what is the width of the road?\n", "id": 549, "options": ["2.91 m", "3 m", "5.82 m", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Permutation And Combination": [{"ans": "D", "question": "\nFrom a group of 7 men and 6 women, five persons are to be selected to form a committee so that at least 3 men are there on the committee. In how many ways can it be done?\n", "id": 550, "options": ["564", "645", "735", "756", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'LEADING' be arranged in such a way that the vowels always come together?", "id": 551, "options": ["360", "480", "720", "5040", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'CORPORATION' be arranged so that the vowels always come together?", "id": 552, "options": ["810", "1440", "2880", "50400", "5760"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Out of 7 consonants and 4 vowels, how many words of 3 consonants and 2 vowels can be formed?", "id": 553, "options": ["210", "1050", "25200", "21400", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In how many ways can the letters of the word 'LEADER' be arranged?\r\n", "id": 554, "options": ["72", "144", "360", "720", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nFrom a group of 7 men and 6 women, five persons are to be selected to form a committee so that at least 3 men are there on the committee. In how many ways can it be done?\n", "id": 555, "options": ["564", "645", "735", "756", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'LEADING' be arranged in such a way that the vowels always come together?", "id": 556, "options": ["360", "480", "720", "5040", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'CORPORATION' be arranged so that the vowels always come together?", "id": 557, "options": ["810", "1440", "2880", "50400", "5760"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Out of 7 consonants and 4 vowels, how many words of 3 consonants and 2 vowels can be formed?", "id": 558, "options": ["210", "1050", "25200", "21400", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In how many ways can the letters of the word 'LEADER' be arranged?\r\n", "id": 559, "options": ["72", "144", "360", "720", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nFrom a group of 7 men and 6 women, five persons are to be selected to form a committee so that at least 3 men are there on the committee. In how many ways can it be done?\n", "id": 560, "options": ["564", "645", "735", "756", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'LEADING' be arranged in such a way that the vowels always come together?", "id": 561, "options": ["360", "480", "720", "5040", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'CORPORATION' be arranged so that the vowels always come together?", "id": 562, "options": ["810", "1440", "2880", "50400", "5760"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Out of 7 consonants and 4 vowels, how many words of 3 consonants and 2 vowels can be formed?", "id": 563, "options": ["210", "1050", "25200", "21400", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "In how many ways can the letters of the word 'LEADER' be arranged?\r\n", "id": 564, "options": ["72", "144", "360", "720", "None of these"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Problems On Numbers": [{"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf one-third of one-fourth of a number is 15, then three-tenth of that number is:\n", "id": 565, "options": ["35", "36", "45", "54"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Three times the first of three consecutive odd integers is 3 more than twice the third. The third integer is:", "id": 566, "options": ["9", "11", "13", "15"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe difference between a two-digit number and the number obtained by interchanging the positions of its digits is 36. What is the difference between the two digits of that number?\n", "id": 567, "options": ["3", "4", "9", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe difference between a two-digit number and the number obtained by interchanging the digits is 36. What is the difference between the sum and the difference of the digits of the number if the ratio between the digits of the number is 1 : 2 ?\n", "id": 568, "options": ["4", "8", "16", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA two-digit number is such that the product of the digits is 8. When 18 is added to the number, then the digits are reversed. The number is:\n", "id": 569, "options": ["18", "24", "42", "81"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf one-third of one-fourth of a number is 15, then three-tenth of that number is:\n", "id": 570, "options": ["35", "36", "45", "54"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Three times the first of three consecutive odd integers is 3 more than twice the third. The third integer is:", "id": 571, "options": ["9", "11", "13", "15"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe difference between a two-digit number and the number obtained by interchanging the positions of its digits is 36. What is the difference between the two digits of that number?\n", "id": 572, "options": ["3", "4", "9", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe difference between a two-digit number and the number obtained by interchanging the digits is 36. What is the difference between the sum and the difference of the digits of the number if the ratio between the digits of the number is 1 : 2 ?\n", "id": 573, "options": ["4", "8", "16", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA two-digit number is such that the product of the digits is 8. When 18 is added to the number, then the digits are reversed. The number is:\n", "id": 574, "options": ["18", "24", "42", "81"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf one-third of one-fourth of a number is 15, then three-tenth of that number is:\n", "id": 575, "options": ["35", "36", "45", "54"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Three times the first of three consecutive odd integers is 3 more than twice the third. The third integer is:", "id": 576, "options": ["9", "11", "13", "15"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe difference between a two-digit number and the number obtained by interchanging the positions of its digits is 36. What is the difference between the two digits of that number?\n", "id": 577, "options": ["3", "4", "9", "Cannot be determined", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe difference between a two-digit number and the number obtained by interchanging the digits is 36. What is the difference between the sum and the difference of the digits of the number if the ratio between the digits of the number is 1 : 2 ?\n", "id": 578, "options": ["4", "8", "16", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA two-digit number is such that the product of the digits is 8. When 18 is added to the number, then the digits are reversed. The number is:\n", "id": 579, "options": ["18", "24", "42", "81"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Decimal Fraction": [{"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nEvaluate :\n(2.39)2 - (1.61)2\n\n\n2.39 - 1.61\n\n\n", "id": 580, "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nWhat decimal of an hour is a second ?\n", "id": 581, "options": [".0025", ".0256", ".00027", ".000126"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n(0.96)3 - (0.1)3 \nis:\n\n\n(0.96)2 + 0.096 + (0.1)2\n\n\n", "id": 582, "options": ["0.86", "0.95", "0.97", "1.06"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n0.1 x 0.1 x 0.1 + 0.02 x 0.02 x 0.02\nis:\n\n\n0.2 x 0.2 x 0.2 + 0.04 x 0.04 x 0.04\n\n\n", "id": 583, "options": ["0.0125", "0.125", "0.25", "0.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "If 2994 \u00f7 14.5 = 172, then 29.94 \u00f7 1.45 = ?", "id": 584, "options": ["0.172", "1.72", "17.2", "172"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nEvaluate :\n(2.39)2 - (1.61)2\n\n\n2.39 - 1.61\n\n\n", "id": 585, "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nWhat decimal of an hour is a second ?\n", "id": 586, "options": [".0025", ".0256", ".00027", ".000126"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n(0.96)3 - (0.1)3 \nis:\n\n\n(0.96)2 + 0.096 + (0.1)2\n\n\n", "id": 587, "options": ["0.86", "0.95", "0.97", "1.06"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n0.1 x 0.1 x 0.1 + 0.02 x 0.02 x 0.02\nis:\n\n\n0.2 x 0.2 x 0.2 + 0.04 x 0.04 x 0.04\n\n\n", "id": 588, "options": ["0.0125", "0.125", "0.25", "0.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "If 2994 \u00f7 14.5 = 172, then 29.94 \u00f7 1.45 = ?", "id": 589, "options": ["0.172", "1.72", "17.2", "172"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nEvaluate :\n(2.39)2 - (1.61)2\n\n\n2.39 - 1.61\n\n\n", "id": 590, "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nWhat decimal of an hour is a second ?\n", "id": 591, "options": [".0025", ".0256", ".00027", ".000126"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n(0.96)3 - (0.1)3 \nis:\n\n\n(0.96)2 + 0.096 + (0.1)2\n\n\n", "id": 592, "options": ["0.86", "0.95", "0.97", "1.06"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n0.1 x 0.1 x 0.1 + 0.02 x 0.02 x 0.02\nis:\n\n\n0.2 x 0.2 x 0.2 + 0.04 x 0.04 x 0.04\n\n\n", "id": 593, "options": ["0.0125", "0.125", "0.25", "0.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "If 2994 \u00f7 14.5 = 172, then 29.94 \u00f7 1.45 = ?", "id": 594, "options": ["0.172", "1.72", "17.2", "172"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nEvaluate :\n(2.39)2 - (1.61)2\n\n\n2.39 - 1.61\n\n\n", "id": 595, "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nWhat decimal of an hour is a second ?\n", "id": 596, "options": [".0025", ".0256", ".00027", ".000126"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n(0.96)3 - (0.1)3 \nis:\n\n\n(0.96)2 + 0.096 + (0.1)2\n\n\n", "id": 597, "options": ["0.86", "0.95", "0.97", "1.06"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n0.1 x 0.1 x 0.1 + 0.02 x 0.02 x 0.02\nis:\n\n\n0.2 x 0.2 x 0.2 + 0.04 x 0.04 x 0.04\n\n\n", "id": 598, "options": ["0.0125", "0.125", "0.25", "0.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "If 2994 \u00f7 14.5 = 172, then 29.94 \u00f7 1.45 = ?", "id": 599, "options": ["0.172", "1.72", "17.2", "172"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nEvaluate :\n(2.39)2 - (1.61)2\n\n\n2.39 - 1.61\n\n\n", "id": 600, "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nWhat decimal of an hour is a second ?\n", "id": 601, "options": [".0025", ".0256", ".00027", ".000126"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n(0.96)3 - (0.1)3 \nis:\n\n\n(0.96)2 + 0.096 + (0.1)2\n\n\n", "id": 602, "options": ["0.86", "0.95", "0.97", "1.06"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n0.1 x 0.1 x 0.1 + 0.02 x 0.02 x 0.02\nis:\n\n\n0.2 x 0.2 x 0.2 + 0.04 x 0.04 x 0.04\n\n\n", "id": 603, "options": ["0.0125", "0.125", "0.25", "0.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "If 2994 \u00f7 14.5 = 172, then 29.94 \u00f7 1.45 = ?", "id": 604, "options": ["0.172", "1.72", "17.2", "172"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nEvaluate :\n(2.39)2 - (1.61)2\n\n\n2.39 - 1.61\n\n\n", "id": 605, "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nWhat decimal of an hour is a second ?\n", "id": 606, "options": [".0025", ".0256", ".00027", ".000126"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n(0.96)3 - (0.1)3 \nis:\n\n\n(0.96)2 + 0.096 + (0.1)2\n\n\n", "id": 607, "options": ["0.86", "0.95", "0.97", "1.06"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\n\n\nThe value of\n0.1 x 0.1 x 0.1 + 0.02 x 0.02 x 0.02\nis:\n\n\n0.2 x 0.2 x 0.2 + 0.04 x 0.04 x 0.04\n\n\n", "id": 608, "options": ["0.0125", "0.125", "0.25", "0.5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "If 2994 \u00f7 14.5 = 172, then 29.94 \u00f7 1.45 = ?", "id": 609, "options": ["0.172", "1.72", "17.2", "172"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Square Root And Cube Root": [{"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe cube root of .000216 is:\n", "id": 610, "options": [".6", ".06", "77", "87"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nWhat should come in place of both x in the equation\nx\n=\n162\n.\n\n\n128\nx\n\n\n", "id": 611, "options": ["12", "14", "144", "196"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe least perfect square, which is divisible by each of 21, 36 and 66 is:\n", "id": 612, "options": ["213444", "214344", "214434", "231444"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "1.5625 = ?\n", "id": 613, "options": ["1.05", "1.25", "1.45", "1.55"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf 35 + 125 = 17.88, then what will be the value of 80 + 65 ?\n", "id": 614, "options": ["13.41", "20.46", "21.66", "22.35"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe cube root of .000216 is:\n", "id": 615, "options": [".6", ".06", "77", "87"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nWhat should come in place of both x in the equation\nx\n=\n162\n.\n\n\n128\nx\n\n\n", "id": 616, "options": ["12", "14", "144", "196"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe least perfect square, which is divisible by each of 21, 36 and 66 is:\n", "id": 617, "options": ["213444", "214344", "214434", "231444"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "1.5625 = ?\n", "id": 618, "options": ["1.05", "1.25", "1.45", "1.55"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf 35 + 125 = 17.88, then what will be the value of 80 + 65 ?\n", "id": 619, "options": ["13.41", "20.46", "21.66", "22.35"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe cube root of .000216 is:\n", "id": 620, "options": [".6", ".06", "77", "87"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\n\n\nWhat should come in place of both x in the equation\nx\n=\n162\n.\n\n\n128\nx\n\n\n", "id": 621, "options": ["12", "14", "144", "196"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe least perfect square, which is divisible by each of 21, 36 and 66 is:\n", "id": 622, "options": ["213444", "214344", "214434", "231444"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "1.5625 = ?\n", "id": 623, "options": ["1.05", "1.25", "1.45", "1.55"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIf 35 + 125 = 17.88, then what will be the value of 80 + 65 ?\n", "id": 624, "options": ["13.41", "20.46", "21.66", "22.35"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Ratio And Proportion": [{"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B together have Rs. 1210. If  of A's amount is equal to  of B's amount, how much amount does B have?\n", "id": 625, "options": ["Rs. 460", "Rs. 484", "Rs. 550", "Rs. 664"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Two numbers are respectively 20% and 50% more than a third number. The ratio of the two numbers is:\r\n", "id": 626, "options": ["2 : 5", "3 : 5", "4 : 5", "6 : 7"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA sum of money is to be distributed among A, B, C, D in the proportion of  5 : 2 : 4 : 3. If C gets Rs. 1000 more than D, what is B's share?\n", "id": 627, "options": ["Rs. 500", "Rs. 1500", "Rs. 2000", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nSeats for Mathematics, Physics and Biology in a school are in the ratio 5 : 7 : 8. There is a proposal to increase these seats by 40%, 50% and 75% respectively. What will be the ratio of increased seats?\n", "id": 628, "options": ["2 : 3 : 4", "6 : 7 : 8", "6 : 8 : 9", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "In a mixture 60 litres, the ratio of milk and water 2 : 1. If this ratio is to be 1 : 2, then the quanity of water to be further added is:", "id": 629, "options": ["20 litres", "30 litres", "40 litres", "60 litres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B together have Rs. 1210. If  of A's amount is equal to  of B's amount, how much amount does B have?\n", "id": 630, "options": ["Rs. 460", "Rs. 484", "Rs. 550", "Rs. 664"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Two numbers are respectively 20% and 50% more than a third number. The ratio of the two numbers is:\r\n", "id": 631, "options": ["2 : 5", "3 : 5", "4 : 5", "6 : 7"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA sum of money is to be distributed among A, B, C, D in the proportion of  5 : 2 : 4 : 3. If C gets Rs. 1000 more than D, what is B's share?\n", "id": 632, "options": ["Rs. 500", "Rs. 1500", "Rs. 2000", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nSeats for Mathematics, Physics and Biology in a school are in the ratio 5 : 7 : 8. There is a proposal to increase these seats by 40%, 50% and 75% respectively. What will be the ratio of increased seats?\n", "id": 633, "options": ["2 : 3 : 4", "6 : 7 : 8", "6 : 8 : 9", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "In a mixture 60 litres, the ratio of milk and water 2 : 1. If this ratio is to be 1 : 2, then the quanity of water to be further added is:", "id": 634, "options": ["20 litres", "30 litres", "40 litres", "60 litres"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B together have Rs. 1210. If  of A's amount is equal to  of B's amount, how much amount does B have?\n", "id": 635, "options": ["Rs. 460", "Rs. 484", "Rs. 550", "Rs. 664"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Two numbers are respectively 20% and 50% more than a third number. The ratio of the two numbers is:\r\n", "id": 636, "options": ["2 : 5", "3 : 5", "4 : 5", "6 : 7"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA sum of money is to be distributed among A, B, C, D in the proportion of  5 : 2 : 4 : 3. If C gets Rs. 1000 more than D, what is B's share?\n", "id": 637, "options": ["Rs. 500", "Rs. 1500", "Rs. 2000", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nSeats for Mathematics, Physics and Biology in a school are in the ratio 5 : 7 : 8. There is a proposal to increase these seats by 40%, 50% and 75% respectively. What will be the ratio of increased seats?\n", "id": 638, "options": ["2 : 3 : 4", "6 : 7 : 8", "6 : 8 : 9", "None of these"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "In a mixture 60 litres, the ratio of milk and water 2 : 1. If this ratio is to be 1 : 2, then the quanity of water to be further added is:", "id": 639, "options": ["20 litres", "30 litres", "40 litres", "60 litres"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Pipes And Cistern": [{"ans": "B", "question": "\nThree pipes A, B and C can fill a tank from empty to full in 30 minutes, 20 minutes, and 10 minutes respectively. When the tank is empty, all the three pipes are opened. A, B and C discharge chemical solutions P,Q and R respectively. What is the proportion of the solution R in the liquid in the tank after 3 minutes?\n", "id": 640, "options": ["\n\n\n5\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n6\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n11\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nPipes A and B can fill a tank in 5 and 6 hours respectively. Pipe C can empty it in 12 hours. If all the three pipes are opened together, then the tank will be filled in:\n", "id": 641, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n13\nhours\n\n\n17\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n8\nhours\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n9\nhours\n\n\n17\n\n\n", "\n\n\n4\n1\nhours\n\n\n2\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A pump can fill a tank with water in 2 hours. Because of a leak, it took 2 hours to fill the tank. The leak can drain all the water of the tank in:", "id": 642, "options": ["\n\n4\n1\nhours\n\n\n3\n\n", "7 hours", "8 hours", "14 hours"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo pipes A and B can fill a cistern in 37 minutes and 45 minutes respectively. Both pipes are opened. The cistern will be filled in just half an hour, if the B is turned off after:\n", "id": 643, "options": ["5 min.", "9 min.", "10 min.", "15 min."]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA tank is filled by three pipes with uniform flow. The first two pipes operating simultaneously fill the tank in the same time during which the tank is filled by the third pipe alone. The second pipe fills the tank 5 hours faster than the first pipe and 4 hours slower than the third pipe. The time required by the first pipe is:\n", "id": 644, "options": ["6 hours", "10 hours", "15 hours", "30 hours"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThree pipes A, B and C can fill a tank from empty to full in 30 minutes, 20 minutes, and 10 minutes respectively. When the tank is empty, all the three pipes are opened. A, B and C discharge chemical solutions P,Q and R respectively. What is the proportion of the solution R in the liquid in the tank after 3 minutes?\n", "id": 645, "options": ["\n\n\n5\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n6\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n11\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nPipes A and B can fill a tank in 5 and 6 hours respectively. Pipe C can empty it in 12 hours. If all the three pipes are opened together, then the tank will be filled in:\n", "id": 646, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n13\nhours\n\n\n17\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n8\nhours\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n9\nhours\n\n\n17\n\n\n", "\n\n\n4\n1\nhours\n\n\n2\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A pump can fill a tank with water in 2 hours. Because of a leak, it took 2 hours to fill the tank. The leak can drain all the water of the tank in:", "id": 647, "options": ["\n\n4\n1\nhours\n\n\n3\n\n", "7 hours", "8 hours", "14 hours"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo pipes A and B can fill a cistern in 37 minutes and 45 minutes respectively. Both pipes are opened. The cistern will be filled in just half an hour, if the B is turned off after:\n", "id": 648, "options": ["5 min.", "9 min.", "10 min.", "15 min."]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA tank is filled by three pipes with uniform flow. The first two pipes operating simultaneously fill the tank in the same time during which the tank is filled by the third pipe alone. The second pipe fills the tank 5 hours faster than the first pipe and 4 hours slower than the third pipe. The time required by the first pipe is:\n", "id": 649, "options": ["6 hours", "10 hours", "15 hours", "30 hours"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThree pipes A, B and C can fill a tank from empty to full in 30 minutes, 20 minutes, and 10 minutes respectively. When the tank is empty, all the three pipes are opened. A, B and C discharge chemical solutions P,Q and R respectively. What is the proportion of the solution R in the liquid in the tank after 3 minutes?\n", "id": 650, "options": ["\n\n\n5\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n6\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n11\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nPipes A and B can fill a tank in 5 and 6 hours respectively. Pipe C can empty it in 12 hours. If all the three pipes are opened together, then the tank will be filled in:\n", "id": 651, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n13\nhours\n\n\n17\n\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n8\nhours\n\n\n11\n\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n9\nhours\n\n\n17\n\n\n", "\n\n\n4\n1\nhours\n\n\n2\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "A pump can fill a tank with water in 2 hours. Because of a leak, it took 2 hours to fill the tank. The leak can drain all the water of the tank in:", "id": 652, "options": ["\n\n4\n1\nhours\n\n\n3\n\n", "7 hours", "8 hours", "14 hours"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nTwo pipes A and B can fill a cistern in 37 minutes and 45 minutes respectively. Both pipes are opened. The cistern will be filled in just half an hour, if the B is turned off after:\n", "id": 653, "options": ["5 min.", "9 min.", "10 min.", "15 min."]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nA tank is filled by three pipes with uniform flow. The first two pipes operating simultaneously fill the tank in the same time during which the tank is filled by the third pipe alone. The second pipe fills the tank 5 hours faster than the first pipe and 4 hours slower than the third pipe. The time required by the first pipe is:\n", "id": 654, "options": ["6 hours", "10 hours", "15 hours", "30 hours"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Alligation Or Mixture": [{"ans": "C", "question": "A vessel is filled with liquid, 3 parts of which are water and 5 parts syrup. How much of the mixture must be drawn off and replaced with water so that the mixture may be half water and half syrup?", "id": 655, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n5\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n7\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Tea worth Rs. 126 per kg and Rs. 135 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 1 : 1 : 2. If the mixture is worth Rs. 153 per kg, the price of the third variety per kg will be:", "id": 656, "options": ["Rs. 169.50", "Rs. 170", "Rs. 175.50", "Rs. 180"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can contains a mixture of two liquids A and B is the ratio 7 : 5. When 9 litres of mixture are drawn off and the can is filled with B, the ratio of A and B becomes 7 : 9. How many litres of liquid A was contained by the can initially?", "id": 657, "options": ["10", "20", "21", "25"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A milk vendor has 2 cans of milk. The first contains 25% water and the rest milk. The second contains 50% water. How much milk should he mix from each of the containers so as to get 12 litres of milk such that the ratio of water to milk is 3 : 5?\n", "id": 658, "options": ["4 litres, 8 litres", "6 litres, 6 litres", "5 litres, 7 litres", "7 litres, 5 litres"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIn what ratio must a grocer mix two varieties of pulses costing Rs. 15 and Rs. 20 per kg respectively so as to get a mixture worth Rs. 16.50 kg?\n", "id": 659, "options": ["3 : 7", "5 : 7", "7 : 3", "7 : 5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A vessel is filled with liquid, 3 parts of which are water and 5 parts syrup. How much of the mixture must be drawn off and replaced with water so that the mixture may be half water and half syrup?", "id": 660, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n5\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n7\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Tea worth Rs. 126 per kg and Rs. 135 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 1 : 1 : 2. If the mixture is worth Rs. 153 per kg, the price of the third variety per kg will be:", "id": 661, "options": ["Rs. 169.50", "Rs. 170", "Rs. 175.50", "Rs. 180"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can contains a mixture of two liquids A and B is the ratio 7 : 5. When 9 litres of mixture are drawn off and the can is filled with B, the ratio of A and B becomes 7 : 9. How many litres of liquid A was contained by the can initially?", "id": 662, "options": ["10", "20", "21", "25"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A milk vendor has 2 cans of milk. The first contains 25% water and the rest milk. The second contains 50% water. How much milk should he mix from each of the containers so as to get 12 litres of milk such that the ratio of water to milk is 3 : 5?\n", "id": 663, "options": ["4 litres, 8 litres", "6 litres, 6 litres", "5 litres, 7 litres", "7 litres, 5 litres"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIn what ratio must a grocer mix two varieties of pulses costing Rs. 15 and Rs. 20 per kg respectively so as to get a mixture worth Rs. 16.50 kg?\n", "id": 664, "options": ["3 : 7", "5 : 7", "7 : 3", "7 : 5"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A vessel is filled with liquid, 3 parts of which are water and 5 parts syrup. How much of the mixture must be drawn off and replaced with water so that the mixture may be half water and half syrup?", "id": 665, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n5\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n7\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "Tea worth Rs. 126 per kg and Rs. 135 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 1 : 1 : 2. If the mixture is worth Rs. 153 per kg, the price of the third variety per kg will be:", "id": 666, "options": ["Rs. 169.50", "Rs. 170", "Rs. 175.50", "Rs. 180"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "A can contains a mixture of two liquids A and B is the ratio 7 : 5. When 9 litres of mixture are drawn off and the can is filled with B, the ratio of A and B becomes 7 : 9. How many litres of liquid A was contained by the can initially?", "id": 667, "options": ["10", "20", "21", "25"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "A milk vendor has 2 cans of milk. The first contains 25% water and the rest milk. The second contains 50% water. How much milk should he mix from each of the containers so as to get 12 litres of milk such that the ratio of water to milk is 3 : 5?\n", "id": 668, "options": ["4 litres, 8 litres", "6 litres, 6 litres", "5 litres, 7 litres", "7 litres, 5 litres"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIn what ratio must a grocer mix two varieties of pulses costing Rs. 15 and Rs. 20 per kg respectively so as to get a mixture worth Rs. 16.50 kg?\n", "id": 669, "options": ["3 : 7", "5 : 7", "7 : 3", "7 : 5"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Races And Games": [{"ans": "B", "question": "\nIn a 100 m race, A can give B 10 m and C 28 m. In the same race B can give C:\n", "id": 670, "options": ["18 m", "20 m", "27 m", "9 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B take part in 100 m race. A runs at 5 kmph. A gives B a start of 8 m and still beats him by 8 seconds. The speed of B is:\n", "id": 671, "options": ["5.15 kmph", "4.14 kmph", "4.25 kmph", "4.4 kmph"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIn a 500 m race, the ratio of the speeds of two contestants A and B is 3 : 4. A has a start of 140 m. Then, A wins by:\n", "id": 672, "options": ["60 m", "40 m", "20 m", "10 m"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIn a 100 m race, A beats B by 10 m and C by 13 m. In a race of 180 m, B will beat C by:\n", "id": 673, "options": ["5.4 m", "4.5 m", "5 m", "6 m"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nAt a game of billiards, A can give B 15 points in 60 and A can give C to 20 points in 60. How many points can B give C in a game of 90?\n", "id": 674, "options": ["30 points", "20 points", "10 points", "12 points"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nIn a 100 m race, A can give B 10 m and C 28 m. In the same race B can give C:\n", "id": 675, "options": ["18 m", "20 m", "27 m", "9 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B take part in 100 m race. A runs at 5 kmph. A gives B a start of 8 m and still beats him by 8 seconds. The speed of B is:\n", "id": 676, "options": ["5.15 kmph", "4.14 kmph", "4.25 kmph", "4.4 kmph"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIn a 500 m race, the ratio of the speeds of two contestants A and B is 3 : 4. A has a start of 140 m. Then, A wins by:\n", "id": 677, "options": ["60 m", "40 m", "20 m", "10 m"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIn a 100 m race, A beats B by 10 m and C by 13 m. In a race of 180 m, B will beat C by:\n", "id": 678, "options": ["5.4 m", "4.5 m", "5 m", "6 m"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nAt a game of billiards, A can give B 15 points in 60 and A can give C to 20 points in 60. How many points can B give C in a game of 90?\n", "id": 679, "options": ["30 points", "20 points", "10 points", "12 points"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nIn a 100 m race, A can give B 10 m and C 28 m. In the same race B can give C:\n", "id": 680, "options": ["18 m", "20 m", "27 m", "9 m"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nA and B take part in 100 m race. A runs at 5 kmph. A gives B a start of 8 m and still beats him by 8 seconds. The speed of B is:\n", "id": 681, "options": ["5.15 kmph", "4.14 kmph", "4.25 kmph", "4.4 kmph"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nIn a 500 m race, the ratio of the speeds of two contestants A and B is 3 : 4. A has a start of 140 m. Then, A wins by:\n", "id": 682, "options": ["60 m", "40 m", "20 m", "10 m"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nIn a 100 m race, A beats B by 10 m and C by 13 m. In a race of 180 m, B will beat C by:\n", "id": 683, "options": ["5.4 m", "4.5 m", "5 m", "6 m"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nAt a game of billiards, A can give B 15 points in 60 and A can give C to 20 points in 60. How many points can B give C in a game of 90?\n", "id": 684, "options": ["30 points", "20 points", "10 points", "12 points"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Probability": [{"ans": "D", "question": "Tickets numbered 1 to 20 are mixed up and then a ticket is drawn at random. What is the probability that the ticket drawn has a number which is a multiple of 3 or 5?\r\n", "id": 685, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n", "\n\n2\n\n\n5\n\n", "\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n", "\n\n9\n\n\n20\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA bag contains 2 red, 3 green and 2 blue balls. Two balls are drawn at random. What is the probability that none of the balls drawn is blue?\n", "id": 686, "options": ["\n\n10\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n11\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n\n5\n\n\n7\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIn a box, there are 8 red, 7 blue and 6 green balls. One ball is picked up randomly. What is the probability that it is neither red nor green?\n", "id": 687, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n\n\n4\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n19\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n\n\n21\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What is the probability of getting a sum 9 from two throws of a dice?", "id": 688, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n6\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n9\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n12\n\n"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThree unbiased coins are tossed. What is the probability of getting at most two heads?\n", "id": 689, "options": ["\n\n\n3\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n\n\n8\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n8\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Tickets numbered 1 to 20 are mixed up and then a ticket is drawn at random. What is the probability that the ticket drawn has a number which is a multiple of 3 or 5?\r\n", "id": 690, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n", "\n\n2\n\n\n5\n\n", "\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n", "\n\n9\n\n\n20\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA bag contains 2 red, 3 green and 2 blue balls. Two balls are drawn at random. What is the probability that none of the balls drawn is blue?\n", "id": 691, "options": ["\n\n10\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n11\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n\n5\n\n\n7\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIn a box, there are 8 red, 7 blue and 6 green balls. One ball is picked up randomly. What is the probability that it is neither red nor green?\n", "id": 692, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n\n\n4\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n19\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n\n\n21\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What is the probability of getting a sum 9 from two throws of a dice?", "id": 693, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n6\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n9\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n12\n\n"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThree unbiased coins are tossed. What is the probability of getting at most two heads?\n", "id": 694, "options": ["\n\n\n3\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n\n\n8\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n8\n\n\n"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "Tickets numbered 1 to 20 are mixed up and then a ticket is drawn at random. What is the probability that the ticket drawn has a number which is a multiple of 3 or 5?\r\n", "id": 695, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n2\n\n", "\n\n2\n\n\n5\n\n", "\n\n8\n\n\n15\n\n", "\n\n9\n\n\n20\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nA bag contains 2 red, 3 green and 2 blue balls. Two balls are drawn at random. What is the probability that none of the balls drawn is blue?\n", "id": 696, "options": ["\n\n10\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n11\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n2\n\n\n7\n\n", "\n\n\n5\n\n\n7\n\n"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nIn a box, there are 8 red, 7 blue and 6 green balls. One ball is picked up randomly. What is the probability that it is neither red nor green?\n", "id": 697, "options": ["\n\n\n1\n\n\n3\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n\n\n4\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n19\n\n", "\n\n\n8\n\n\n21\n\n", "\n\n\n9\n\n\n21\n\n"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "What is the probability of getting a sum 9 from two throws of a dice?", "id": 698, "options": ["\n\n1\n\n\n6\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n8\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n9\n\n", "\n\n1\n\n\n12\n\n"]}, {"ans": "D", "question": "\nThree unbiased coins are tossed. What is the probability of getting at most two heads?\n", "id": 699, "options": ["\n\n\n3\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n1\n\n\n4\n\n\n", "\n\n\n3\n\n\n8\n\n\n", "\n\n\n7\n\n\n8\n\n\n"]}]}}{"Aptitude": {"Bankers Discount": [{"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on a bill due 4 months hence at 15% is Rs. 420. The true discount is:\n", "id": 700, "options": ["Rs. 400", "Rs. 360", "Rs. 480", "Rs. 320"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on Rs. 1600 at 15% per annum is the same as true discount on Rs. 1680 for the same time and at the same rate. The time is:\n", "id": 701, "options": ["3 months", "4 months", "6 months", "8 months"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's gain of a certain sum due 2 years hence at 10% per annum is Rs. 24. The present worth is:\n", "id": 702, "options": ["Rs. 480", "Rs. 520", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 960"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on a sum of money for 1 years is Rs. 558 and the true discount on the same sum for 2 years is Rs. 600. The rate percent is:\n", "id": 703, "options": ["10%", "13%", "12%", "15%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's gain on a sum due 3 years hence at 12% per annum is Rs. 270. The banker's discount is:\n", "id": 704, "options": ["Rs. 960", "Rs. 840", "Rs. 1020", "Rs. 760"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on a bill due 4 months hence at 15% is Rs. 420. The true discount is:\n", "id": 705, "options": ["Rs. 400", "Rs. 360", "Rs. 480", "Rs. 320"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on Rs. 1600 at 15% per annum is the same as true discount on Rs. 1680 for the same time and at the same rate. The time is:\n", "id": 706, "options": ["3 months", "4 months", "6 months", "8 months"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's gain of a certain sum due 2 years hence at 10% per annum is Rs. 24. The present worth is:\n", "id": 707, "options": ["Rs. 480", "Rs. 520", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 960"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on a sum of money for 1 years is Rs. 558 and the true discount on the same sum for 2 years is Rs. 600. The rate percent is:\n", "id": 708, "options": ["10%", "13%", "12%", "15%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's gain on a sum due 3 years hence at 12% per annum is Rs. 270. The banker's discount is:\n", "id": 709, "options": ["Rs. 960", "Rs. 840", "Rs. 1020", "Rs. 760"]}, {"ans": "A", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on a bill due 4 months hence at 15% is Rs. 420. The true discount is:\n", "id": 710, "options": ["Rs. 400", "Rs. 360", "Rs. 480", "Rs. 320"]}, {"ans": "B", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on Rs. 1600 at 15% per annum is the same as true discount on Rs. 1680 for the same time and at the same rate. The time is:\n", "id": 711, "options": ["3 months", "4 months", "6 months", "8 months"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's gain of a certain sum due 2 years hence at 10% per annum is Rs. 24. The present worth is:\n", "id": 712, "options": ["Rs. 480", "Rs. 520", "Rs. 600", "Rs. 960"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's discount on a sum of money for 1 years is Rs. 558 and the true discount on the same sum for 2 years is Rs. 600. The rate percent is:\n", "id": 713, "options": ["10%", "13%", "12%", "15%"]}, {"ans": "C", "question": "\nThe banker's gain on a sum due 3 years hence at 12% per annum is Rs. 270. The banker's discount is:\n", "id": 714, "options": ["Rs. 960", "Rs. 840", "Rs. 1020", "Rs. 760"]}]}}